Game 11

Game Day

Game Date: 11/07/16

In Play Date:: (5) Mirtul 09, 1491; (10) Marpenoth 3, 1491

TLDR

Tyelknowle didn’t return to the camp like he told Josephus he would. Rowena went looking for him.
Rowena came running back quickly. She was being chased by some kind of Troll monster.
They fought and killed the Beast. The Beast was confused why Rowena, an “earth Mage” was attacking him.
The Heroes tried to trick the guards, but that didn’t work. Barikhol broke open the side door. They opened the first door to their left and it turned out to be a Monk training room.
Inside a Monk named Hellenrae. The heroes and she fought. She took the heroes down one by one and after each hero would fall, she gave the option for the rest of the heroes to leave. They did not and she eventually captured them all.
Josephus didn’t survive the fight.
Tyelknowle was captured by the beast from the beginning. He finally got free, but too late to help his friends. Ty picked up his things and went searching for the Mud-Bloods.
In the end he found them, five months later.

Detailed Entry

{Note from Storyteller: Forgive me. I have a real problem with switching between past and present tense. I do not have any formal training on writing stories. I kind of wanted to spend a couple electives on a class to make me better, but all my electives got bought up with all the classes KSU didn't approve towards my degree. So, Enjoy the story, fix errors in your head where needed. Let me know if I need to fix anything.}

/Cut Scene\

Tyelknowle told Josephus , "I will meet you back at camp. I am going to watch the other side and hopefully see some activity inside. This place is a lot quieter than I thought."

Ty found an advantage point where he could see through the glass roof into a garden and could see into the rear side of the monastery. While he was watching Ty heard a noise that came flying out of the bushes. In a blink of the eye Ty had his dagger out and ready to throw.

The beast turned out to be a rabbit. It would actually have made a good food for later. Just before Ty threw the knife the area got really dark. When he turned around he got blindsided by the handle of a sword.

Tyelknole woke to sunlight hitting his face. He was locked in a cage and could hear fighting off in the distance. From the magic burst and battle yells he could tell were his friends. Ty inspected the cage. It was made out of sturdy wood and the door was tied shut in a thick complicated knot. The rope was heavy and difficult to manipulate. Ty could see his equipment just out of reach of the cage.

Using his clothes he took them off and tied them in a knot. He flung them out to try and wrap around his pack. Ty was nervous the beast would return, so between each throw he would listen. He finally got his shirt to pull his knife close enough to where he could reach his foot out and grab it.

Ty started cutting the rope.

/End Cut Scene\

***Earlier***

Everyone returned to the camp, everyone, that is, except Ty. Josephus said "He will be back soon. We should wait for him." After some time passed the party started to worry that he was not going to return.

Rowena went scouting for Ty. Josephus tried watching her from a vantage point, but eventually lost her to the darkness. Rowena found some tracks that lead her to a good lookout point that can see into the monastery. She peered over a rock to take a look.

Rowena felt her ear twitch. She had the feeling she was no longer alone. She turned around and saw this monstrous beast bring down a sword onto her. She dived out of the way and ran. After some close encounters with the beast almost catching her Rowena finally made it back to the camp where the others were alerted to her coming with company, by Josephus .

The beast was strong and could do some powerful damage. During the fight Rowena tried to grab it with "Max's Earthen Grasp". The creature got confused and said "Earth Mage, why are you attacking me?" Eventually, Armond cast a spell that covered himself in ice shards and taunted the beast. The beast took two attacks on him and the ice shards shot through the beast and put it down.

The beast was laying on the ground trying to breathe, but having difficulty. Rowena walked up to it and it asked, "Earth Mage, did I not serve the Cult of the Black Earth well?

Rowena said, "No, you did good. You can rest in peace now."

The beast said, "I… don't… understand." and he went to sleep. The beast started to disintegrate till he was nothing but a pile of sand on the ground.

The heroes took a rest and when Ty didn't return in the night, they feared the worst and came up with a plan to get into the monastery.

The choice was to attack the monastery or take guards clothes and pose as them to get into the monastery.

Rowena played the part as the damsel in distress. She was pretending that she broke her ankle. She got the guards attention, but as they started to approach, something showed from Rowena that something wasn't right and the guards looked at each other, then started to run to the building.

Rowena yelled "Wait!" and sounded convincing enough the guards paused.

She started stumbling up to them when one of the guards asked "Wasn't it your other leg?"

Rowena replied, "ummmm…"

They ran towards the front doors: Josephus shot an arrow. Barikhol threw his throwing axe. Armond blasted at them, but missed. Rowena casted sleep and took down one of the one of the guards. The other guard kept running and the doors opened up when he ran up.

The heroes took the fallen guard and ran off.

They found a place in the woods, stripped him, tied him up, and splashed water on him to wake him up. They questioned him about how many people were in the monastery and if they have taken a half elf as a prisoner. The guard wouldn't speak, but Armond can be very convincing with a knife into the leg. After a bit of screaming he admitted there were at least 50 inside. He tried to say that he doesn't know of any half elf, but Josephus felt there was deceit behind his words.

They tried to get more out of him, but the guard shutdown. He told Armond , "kill me if you must, but I am not saying another word."

Armond replied with, "ok." And then he slit the guard’s throat.

They decided to break into the Monastery. Barikhol and Rowena snuck up to the side door. Barikhol kicked open the door. Right after the sounds from the room to the left got really quiet.

Barikhol walks up to the door and opens it. Inside was a dojo. There was a female tiefling and 4 human students. She says to the group of monks facing the intruders "Class, our guest are here to learn how to dance, let's show them what you have learned."

The fight began. Josephus and Barikhol jumped into the room and started taking down the monks. Armond ran outside to see a spot through the window so he can misty-step in. Rowena ran around the other side to go in through another door to attack the monks from behind.

Josephus and Barikhol knocked out one of the fighters, Rowena casted sleep to drop the rest, the last person standing was the Tiefling. She stood her ground ready for the heroes. The moment one of them moved she darted lightning quick dropping Barikhol . Josephus swung his sword at her and she blocked it, catching it by clasping her hands on the flat of the blade. Rowena casted "Max's Earthen Grasp". The Monk punched her way out of the earthly hand.

"I train with earth mages, like you, daily". The monk said. She took two quick jabs at Josephus and kicked him in the head knocking him out. Armond blasted a black and red bolt, which slammed into the tiefling knocking her against the wall. Rowena sent fire blast flames from her back, which burst in a set of 3 on the tiefling monk.

The tiefling monk kicked off the wall and landed in front of Rowena . After a combo of blows Rowena fell to the floor.

On the ground Josephus opened up his eye and was sliding something out of his pocket. He popped open a bottle of healing potion and took a drink. He popped open a second bottle and gave it to Barikhol . Armond blasted the tiefling from behind sending her out into the hall way.

She hollers back, "I am giving you a choice. You can leave, or I can come back in."

Barikhol questioned, "What do you mean come back in?"

In reply the Tiefling jumped over Rowena back into the room. She took up a fighting stance.

Barikhol walked over to her and bowed. In reply the Tiefling went to kick him in the head. She missed. Barikhol said "we will take our friend and leave."

"No, she is mine." the Tiefling replied.

Josephus said, "Poo Poo on this." (It was a great line, I know Josephus used it somewhere else, but it felt better here) and jumped in to attack the tiefling. He took a couple of blows, a kick to the throat, and went down.

The tiefling said. "I will give you this choice again. These two are forfeit."

Barikhol and Armond looked at each other. After a moments look Armond said, "We have come this far…" Then blasted at the Tiefling.

"Fools." She said as she deflected Barikhols strikes. She then did a combo of blows to him taking him out of the fight.

"Last chance." The tiefling said. She was winded. She was bleeding. She was hurt. "Your friends are mine. Leave!"

"Not a chance." Armond answered. The tiefling charged him. He swung his glaive and she flipped over it kicking him, and following up with a double punch.

Armond fell to the floor.

//Cut scene\\

Soldiers come running into the room. Two run up to the tiefling, "Master Hellenrae , are you hurt?"

She waves them off and points the intruders. "Check them, strip them, and lock them up. These are the heroes of Red Larch that defeated Larrakh . I want to get to know them… intimately."

Tyelknowle stands outside on a hill looking into the window. He was too late. He watched the party get dragged out of the room and away. "There are too many of them. No way am I able to take them on. Tymora what should I do?"

Ty was still getting his gear back together. The Monster went through all his stuff. Ty reaches into his pouch and pulls out a slip of paper. It is a bank deposit receipt. Something Ty has kept on him for many years. He remembers the day this came into his possession.

He was on the streets of Phsant in the country of Thesk. He “acquired” this from a noble man. This was one of his days when he was with the Mud-Bloods .

Ty packs his things and goes. Over the next weeks Ty is seen in different cities speaking to people in Thieves Cant, slipping coins to people, or handing over a bag of goods.

***Later***

Drums playing in a clearing under the canopy of the High Forest. A caravan of travelers seem to have made a permanent structure in the forest. This is their home or at least one of their homes. On a sign near the entrance to this clearing reads, "You are now entering the home of the Mud-Bloods . All who enter here are responsible for themselves as well as their company."

The clearing is a very small town, built for maybe up to 300 people. Their homes are built up in the trees, structures designed by wood-elfs. They have small structures along the road that sells goods (may or may not have been acquired via… donation), structures for place to get a good meal, structures that could work as an inn, and more. Tonight it seems all the towns people have made their way to a very large clearing where they keep their caravans and some of their livestock. They are having a gathering celebrating what seems to be a coming of age for 3 young men.

Sitting on a large chair on a platform is this blue Tiefling female. She is smiling and enjoying the festivities. She looks over at the crowd and her eyes fall on a particular person. Her expression of joy turned into one of shock, like she has seen a ghost.

Tyelknowle comes walking up followed by a stone dwarf. " Joclyn , I have a favor to ask of you."

Game 10.5 | Home | Game Notes | Game 31

Game 31

Detailed Entry

The heroes head south to explore the pool of water. In the middle was a yellow casket. Etched on the side is "Here rests Godwyd the Wyrmbane, dragonslayer and peacekeeper."

The casket contains dust, bones, a cloven skull and helm, and a battered breastplate. A gleaming shortsword is clutched in the skeletons hands. There was also a bag of 600 gold… “was…” Rowena remembered while tapping her pouch on her hip.

The heroes head North where they come across a deep cavern. There is a tiny ledge that one person at a time can make their way across. The difficulty is the wind. It has a mind of its own and it doesn’t wish anyone to cross.

After some discussion, the heroes tied themselves up and attempted to make their way across. After a couple of slips. “SLIPS?” Grimble recalls, “I slammed into the wall twice.”

“If it wasn’t for Rowena I would have gone off the side too!” Leokas said.

“Thank goodness you crawled” Barikhol said

“Not True! I didn’t crawl. Tell him Leokas” Grimble says.

“I literally couldn’t see anything.” Leokas replied.

Once across they were attacked by nine cloaked figures. As the cult members were standing up Rowena skips over there and blast them with cone of cold.

Eight of them shatter, and 1 of them is pinned to the ground.

Traveling a little more north, they run into the guards. Two Bariguras. These are large orange and blue ape like creatures.

Once they fight their way through them, they entered into the summoning room. This is where the heroes battle the god Yan-C-Bin.

Game 11 | Home | Game Notes | Game 31.1 (Armonds Story)

Game 31.1 (Armonds Story)

Detailed Entry

As the heroes of Red Larch vanish through the vanishing glass and all that was left was a small pop. Armond turned to the Mud Bloods and said, “I will work on how we are going to get there, get ready. We leave in a 10 day. Hopefully it will not be traveling by glass.”

On the day of leaving many showed up. Tyelknowle, Wyer, Otho, Joclyn, Finnis, Grund, and Zummy showed up in gear ready to travel. It was also to most others displeasure that Imusek showed up. Unfortunately to travel the underworld on elemental planes Armond had to hire the help of Imusek to open the ways. Fortunately he wasn’t traveling with them.

The heroes traveled to the 4 planes and was able to rescue the souls. Here the souls were formed, but fading. Earth souls were dusting everywhere, Fire souls were slowing smoking away, water souls were turning into a gas, and air souls were leaving floating trails behind them.

One the heroes would collect them up they would open a way and it would send everyone back to Faerun. When the spirits would touch land the theory is they would slowly fade and move on to the afterlife of the path they followed.

The clerics would help them with this transition.

Armond and the rest were meet with plenty of opposition. When they had Fire (the last of the spirits to visit) they went running back though the worlds edge and open the gate. Fighting with tormented spirits they were able to get most through Armond and Ty were the last.

When they went to jump a giant swung his tree and knocked Armond to the ground. Ty turned around and started to go back but the portal was almost closed and he couldn’t get through.

Leaf helps Armond up as they watch the crowd of spirits coming closer. “Well sir… I guess we were not sure if we were coming home anyway.”

“Yeah. Sorry.” Armond tells him.

“Don’t be. It has been an honor.” Leaf tells Armond as they start to gather power. “Let’s make this tough for them.”

Game 31 | Home | Game Notes | Game 14

Feathergale Knights

Overview

A story of the Feathergale Knights

"This first one here was a battle that took place over 100 years ago. This was the first time the hippogriffs went flying into battle. This was obviously before the current Lord Commander.

Waterdeep was under attack by ghost. Waterdeep has griffon riders, but they are 5 riders. Waterdeep knew the ghost were coming but didn't have the man power to hold them back. The ghost were going to make an aerial attack and a group of heroes knew how to defeat them, but they needed time. A group of knights were sent to the Sumber Hills to use the hippogriffs. Waterdeep had a stable out there were they were training hippogriffs, but they have never been ridden into any kind of battle. At least not by the knights of Waterdeep.

The heroes ventured to where the sorcerer was summoning the ghost from and had to fight his undead army to destroy the gym. The Griffon riders of Waterdeep were losing. There were hundreds of ghost and the Griffon Riders are mighty, but even they didn't stand a chance at survival for long.

Then came the sounds of the horns of the Hippogriff riders. This turned the ties of the battle. The knights fought together and were able to hold the ghost back long enough for the adventures on the ground to do their job."

The Feathergale knights have a long history with Waterdeep. They are stationed in spires away from the main city, but normally near cities in which Waterdeep protects. They are hippogriff and vulture riders.

Cast:: Lord Commander Thurl Merosska

Savra Belabrantha - One of the Feathergale Knight Guards

Bringers of Woe | Home | Up | Themes and Threats

Game 15

Game Day

Game Date: 3/18/17

Date in Play: (10) Marpenoth 18, 1491; Red Larch (10) Marpenoth 20, 1491; Necromancer (10) Marpenoth 27, 1491;

TLDR

The beginning of the story started with the heroes arriving at the Vale of Dancing Waters.
They learned about movement of the 4 Cults in Beliard and near IronForge.
The interrogated Larrakh to learn more about Aerisi, the weapon Ironfang, and where the stone armor the Orc were wearing came from.
Barikhol killed Larrakh. Armond and Barikhol got into an argument about this.
At Red Larch the heroes reconnected with everyone.
They got information where the Cult of the Crushing Wave are.
The Lord of Lance Rocks’ father Imuesk came asking for the Dagger of Velsharoon. Armond asked him to join them to get it back.

Detailed Entry

 Our adventure started off with the heroes arriving at the Vale of Dancing Waters. Once they arrived the Mud-Bloods informed the heroes they need to head to Waterdeep. Joclyn was to meet her contact Father Franz. Tyelknowle asked if they would be ok with him joining them.

The rest of the heroes knew they needed to heal up and it was going to take a while. Barikhol and Grimble went into the Vale of Dancing Waters and Barikhol started tending to the sick. He worked for a while, but became exhausted and had to go back out to rest.

Rowena went away from the rest of the survivors to meditate. She found herself in the High Forest, but it was many years ago. She was a child running through the woods. She was chasing after something. She got to a place in the forest and she could no longer see the light from the sun. Looking up at the canopy she could see that it was still day, but the light wasn’t making its way down to her.

She moved further and eventually found the thing she was chasing. It was a fox, no… it was her fox. Rowena’s spirit animal. It is hurt and it was licking its wounds. Rowena sat on the ground and the fox slowly came to her and crawled up in her arms. If she didn’t know any better she would think it felt sick. It was shivering, but it went to sleep.

Armond tracked down one of the prisoners. He was a dwarf. Armond asked him, “You don’t happen to know Brother Eardon do you?”

The Dwarf looked a little suspicious at Armond and answered, “Well, yes. I do. Why do you?”

Armond told him how Brother Eardon was concerned and asked Armond to look into finding the Mirabar Delegation. Armond explained all he knew about the delegation and asked the dwarf if there was anything he saw.

The Dwarf nodded and explained, “We were being chased by something large. It was some kind of burrowing creature. We sent the delegation ahead while four of us stood back to take care of it. We fought it and we lost. One of my brothers in arms died while fighting. The rest of us were captured and taken in. I hoped that the Mirabar Delegation got away, but it appears they did not.”

The Dwarf explained there were 35-40 of them. Armond only remembers seeing roughly 15 or so on the ground where the wreckage was located.

Barikhol and Grimble returned from the Vale of Dancing Waters to find Armond and some others around a campfire. It was a little quiet, but this is probably due to people being locked up for months and some of these people, longer.

Halli made his way down to the camp to meet with the heroes. After he sits down he says “It has been a while since I have heard anything about you all. Some rumored that the Heroes of Red Larch may be dead.”

The heroes explained what has happened to them for the last half a year. How the cults had captured them and put them into slave labor. Halli seems to grow dark at the mention of the cults.

“Their activity has grown. You hear about them more and more these days. Down south there has been battles between the Air and Water cults near Ironforge. I am not sure the Bargewright Inn has been repaired as of yet. In the north, the fire cult terrorized the town of Beliard. Some monks of ours have been up there tending to the wounded and helping rebuild. Stories from all over of children going missing have been making its rounds.” Halli says.

After his stories, some food, and telling everyone goodnight, Halli headed back to the Vale of Dancing Waters and left the travelers to get some rest. After everyone was a sleep Armond, with Barikhol and Grimble, grabbed Larrakh and dragged him away from the others.

They started threatening him, Barikhol and Grimble took turns punching him. Armond finally settled them.

Armond told Larrakh “This is what I want to know. I want to know who Queen Aerisi is. I want to know what Ironfang is. I can make your death quick or I could drag you all the way back to Red Larch.”

Larrakh replied, “I’m used to pain. I have answers for your questions, and I know what you want. So this is what I want. I want to be able to walk away from here. Do we have a deal?”

Armond said “If I let you leave, you leave the Sword Coast and never return. You don’t hurt anyone on the way out.”

Barikhol and Grimble spoke up, “We are not good with that. Larrakh isn’t going to live.”

Armond, Barikhol, and Grimble got into an argument about needing this information. Armond made the point that if they want to do anything about these cults they need to know this, but Barikhol and Grimble didn’t budge. Armond threw his hands up and said, “Then this is a waste of time.” Then he walked away.

Barikhol and Grimble talked and Barikhol told Grimble, “I give you my word, he is not going to harm anyone ever again. Leave me with him.”

Barikhol started negotiating with Larrakh. He told him that he will honor Armonds agreement and if he gives him the information including information about the Orcs with stone armor he will let him live.

{BTW: This should have been a bluff check. He should have had a chance to spot deception}

Larrakh was kind of surprised by this. Larrakh chose his words of “Let me walk out of here” thinking they would never let him live. So Larrakh knew he was going to have to fight for his life, but Barikhol was offering to let him live.

So Larrakh told him everything he wanted to know:

“Aerisi is no queen. Sure she leads the Air Cult, but if she is calling herself Queen she must be power hungry.” Larrakh takes a moment to think. “Aerisi is an elf. Ever since she was a little girl she wanted to fly. It became an obsession to her. This is how Yan-C-Bin, her god, found her. Yan-C-Bin taught her how to grow wings and Aerisi learned the ways of air.”

{Forgive me, I couldn’t remember the order of your questions and some of the actual questions themselves. I should have taken a break and typed some notes.}

Barikhol asked, “The Feathergale Knights, are they her followers?”

Larrakh looked to Barikhol and said, “Aerisi does have some followers, but this is outside the scope of our agreem...”

Barikhol said, “Fine… Fine.” Cutting Larrakh off. “What can you tell me about the knife, Ironfang?”

Larrakh instinct is to protect the Cult of the Black Earth at all cost, but over the last five months he has grown to think these heroes may just have what it takes to bring the Cult down. He takes a second to decide and says, “Ironfang is not a knife. It is a war pick. A war pick infused with the power of Ogremoch. Long ago the Elemental Evil connected with a legendary weapons smith here in this world. It helped him create the four weapons of the elements. Marlos Ur-nrayle was the one to find Ironfag and his devotion to Ogremoch helped those two come together.”

Barikhol asked “What are the other 3 weapons?”

Larrakh replied “I’m sorry, that I will not tell you for that was not part of our deal.”

Barikhol replied, “Fine. Stone Armor with the Orcs. Go.”

Larrakh had to think back. He knew he remembered something about stone armor, but wasn’t sure specifically of the context of the Orcs. So he told Barikhol what he remembered and hopefully that will be enough. “The creatures of less nature were first. The god of evil earth took creatures like Orcs, Trolls, Goblins…”

Barikhol interrupted, “Kobolds?”

Larrakh looked discussed, “gods no. No one wants to work with kobolds. Anyway Ogremoch created from the earth mystical armor. The armor has been passed from generation to generation. The creatures work for the Cult of the Black Earth now. Ogremoch has blessed his armor to others in the cult, but not many ask for it.”

Larrakh thinks if he knows anything else. He doesn’t want to be caught on a technicality. “I believe I have fulfilled the word of our agreement. Has my information been acceptable?”

Barikhol nods, “Yeah… just not enough for me.” and then punches Larrakh in the throat. It was a single strike, but it was laid perfectly. Barikhol could see the surprise on Larrakh’s face, but he could also see the realization that Larrakh knew he was about to die. Larrakh smiled, tried to laugh, but choked and blood came up.

As Larrakh was laying there dying he was angry that he was tricked, but proud that he caused a monk to lose his control and discipline. Hopefully this action will cause Barikhol to one day take up power that Larrakh was releasing into the world. After lots of coughing of blood and convulsing, Larrakh finally laid quiet.

Barikhol picked him up and walked him to the river. After disposing of the body he made his way back to camp.

Once he met up with Armond and Grimble he went over everything he learned from Larrakh. Armond asked “So when does Larrakh leave?”

Barikhol said, “He is not leaving. I killed him.”

This brought Armond and Barikhol into an argument. Armond was asking questions like “How can I trust you?” “Why would you do something like this?” Barikhol took all the hits and would explain, “It is a burden I will have to carry.” Grimble made the argument that “Barikhol didn’t lie to us. He could have told you he let him go, but he didn’t.”

The argument continued as they do. Armond is having a real tough time with this. Unknown directly to the others, Armond looked to Barikhol for guidance. Armond and Barikhol quickly became friends because they have a similar past. They both have been through trials and tribulations that have been comparable. Armond sees a darkness in himself and he struggles every day to control it. Barikhol, being a monk of Ilmater, is a dwarf of upstanding virtue. If Barikhol can go through the things that Armond has gone though and continue to hold on to his integrity, Armond feels that he has a chance. This action is something that Armond can see himself doing, but hopes he doesn’t.

The Heroes found that the Vail of Dancing Waters has monks that will be heading north and some that will be heading south. The heroes are free to travel with them if they would like. They decided that they would like to go back to Red Larch.

Once they arrived in Red Larch, it had that feeling of coming back home. They returned the Wagon and Horse to Stannor. Armond went to see Harburk, Grimble went to the Helm at Highsun, and Barikhol went to go check on his 9 Hammers and a Keg Brewery.

On his way to the 9 Hammers and a Keg Brewery <It needs a name> Barikhol saw out of the corner of his eye someone about to jump him. He got into ready position, but at last second he noticed it was Grund. Grund picked him up into a big ol’ orc hug. Grund told Barikhol all about the happenings around town. He talked about how he became deputy, he even puffed out his chest to show his star. Grund was really excited to go tell everyone they are back, when he ran off Barikhol could see the kids pillaging his “Orc Fingers” cart.

<Storyteller edit here. I made some adjustments to this scene. I am adding a new Soft Theme called “ Finding Ourselves ” based on the events that have been happening. Let me know if you would like to make any changes to this scene as you are in control of your character I am just adding emotions >

When Barikhol entered he saw a person inside his 9 Hammers and a Keg Brewery. After 5 months being away, this was the first thing Barikhol wanted to come back to. Coming back he finds that an intruder is here in his space. This is HIS space! He controls this place. Not someone else. Barikhol started concentrating to regain control. Barikhol is a monk and he shouldn’t be feeling these kinds of feeling about possessions.

Barikhol closes his eyes and allows his other senses to help center him. When he opens his eyes again he is staring into the eye of Grinarv. Barikhol was not sure he had enough meditation practice to prepare him for this.

“Barikhol my old friend. You’re back!” Grinarv said hobbling up to him. “You like it? Grinarv tried to keep it up to your tastes. Here! Here! Come take a look.” Grinarv said as he was trying to show Barikhol around the place. This seemed a bit unlike what Barikol remembers of him. He noticed Grinarv kept the place up to his specs. There were a couple pieces of equipment that failed and Grinarv repaired them. He actually did a pretty good job. He seems to know something about this trade.

Barikol talked him through a couple of things he noticed around the 9 Hammers and a Keg Brewery that Grinarv could do better. Grinarv was grateful for the feedback. Barikhol grabbed Grinarv by the shoulder and told him. “Grinarv, I misjudged you. You have done a really good job here.”

“Barikhol, you were right to judge me. As children Grinarv was an asshole. Grinarv remembers what Grinarv and friends did and said about you and your father.” Grinarv said.. of course in third person. “Your father would have been proud.”

Barikhol nodded, “That means a lot. Thank you.” He took a moment to pause and look around at the place. “It looks like you are going to be on staff, let’s workout finances I can’t think of anyone better I would like to have run the place while I am away.”

Grimble was in the Helm at Highsun. He was seeing all the towns’ people. People of different races and he could tell different backgrounds. This town doesn’t seem like everyone was born here. It makes sense, this is a travel through town. A large man with a chipped tooth and three golden earring approaches the table. “Welcome traveler to the Helm at Highsun. I am Justran, what can I get you?”

Grimble orders some food and ale, and continues watching the people while waiting on his new found acquaintances.

{Cut Scene}

Harburk was chopping poultry going about his business. Harburk has been extremely busy for the last few months. After the mess with Believers , the town got really suspicious of its community. This was very difficult for Harburk combat. Harburk is not very political. He is fair and just. He can enforce order, but being persuasive is just not in his tool belt. He also had to travel south to Waterdeep for the trial of Ilmeth and Elak . This was tough on the soul. He knew these two for many years. They weren’t killers, they just believed in the wrong man, a monster, and made a terrible mistake, one they could not take back. The weight of their execution weighed heavy on him.

{/Cut Scene}

Harburk was deep in thought when the door ringed. A man entered and Harburk said his standard “I’ll be with you in one…” But he didn’t finish. Harburk glanced up to expect to see a townsfolk or a traveler. He never could bring himself to say it, but he thought the Heroes of Red Larch may never return.

Harburk cleaned himself up and walked over to shake Armond’s hand. “Welcome home. It sure is good to see you.” He said.

They caught up, Harburk shared how there was a betting pool if you all were still alive. Explained that Wyer has been taking care of your affairs since you have been gone. Kaylessa will be happy to hear that the room will be used again. Harburk then offered to cover their meals at the Helm at Highsun.

{Cut Scene}

<this is part of a soft theme called “ Finding Ourselves ”. This scene may be a little emotional, but I feel it makes the heroes real. I don’t plan on this game becoming an emo, let’s fall in love with a shiny vampire story, but I would like to explore the heroes making a journey back to themselves. That is why this is a soft theme. This also sets expectations for both Players and Storyteller on how to lead/describe narration. This was also a scene I really wanted to run at the game, but unfortunately couldn’t.>

Rowena came back to the town and wasn’t sure where to go. She went over to the Haeleeya’s Bathhouse to clean up. When she walked in Haeleeya stood up and came running up to her. “the gods have listened, you have returned!” Haeleeya said.

Haeleeya took a quick look at Rowena and could see that her wounds go deeper than just her skin. “it’s ok, you’re safe now.” Haeleeya didn’t know the words to say to help Rowena , and didn’t know if the words existed.

Rowena had not been touched by another human for the last 5 months in a kind way. She wasn’t sure how to process this. Rowena hasn’t had a good year. She joined an adventure party who all but one was slaughtered by zombies. She was captured by the necromancer who killed Odert and placed his soul inside her. She began life with this new adventure party, and they too were captured. She was tortured for 5 months, and now she thinks her spirit fox is dying. Processing this is not an option and Rowena immediately hugs Haeleeya again.

Haeleeya glances over at one of her employees and moves her eyes to indicate for her to prep a bath. Haeleeya let’s Rowena hold on to her for as long as she needs.

The scene cuts and Rowena is taking a long overdue bath. Haeleeya’s younger sister Lippa, who drew Rowena the bath, checks up on her “Is everything to expectations? May I fetch you something to drink?” When Lippa doesn’t hear a reply she glances over to see Rowena trying to answer, but bubbles coming out of her mouth. The employee get nervous as Rowena begins to levitate in a bubble. The bubble floats up to the ceiling and pops and Rowena splashes back down in the bath water.

When she comes crawling out of the bath she looks up at the employee and says “I’m ok.” The employee screams and runs out of the bathhouse. Rowena thought for a second and realized she didn’t say “I’m ok.” She actually didn’t say anything at all. She made some noises, but not words.

Rowena shook, to dry herself and then crawled over to the mirror. “Bark” (translation: “Well Shit”). In the mirror staring back at her is a fox. Rowena saw out the door what looked to be her spirit fox. She decided to follow him.

Out of town they ran, Rowena could visibly see that her spirit fox wasn’t 100%. He was still wounded, still sick. They ran and ran. While on their little adventure, they ran into a… well… Rowena didn’t know what it was. But the thing that could only be described as darkness attacked them. During the fight, Rowena allowed her Wild Magic to spark and could see the stress it caused her Spirit after each burst.

Once Rowena made it home… well snuck back to the bathhouse to retrieve her cloths, then home. She had a lot to think about. On her way to her room, she could feel a wild surge. Rowena suppressed it the best she could and went to her room to get some rest.

{/Cut Scene}

The remainder of the week went pretty smooth. The heroes met with different people around town. There was a moment, where the town paid their respects to Josephus. Everyone in the Helm at Highsun took a piece of crumble bread and the room went around telling stories. Everyone took a bite and chewed… and chewed… and chewed some more Marielye, the bar maid, started laughing first. Then a couple other people. Then eventually the whole room started letting out a gut laugh.

A caravan came rolling through town. It is a known group. They travel in a circle from Mirabar to Waterdeep, then up the coast to Luskan, last back to Mirabar, and then back again. Travelers from all over visited the stores and shops. It was a good day for Red Larch.

That evening two beautiful women entered the Helm at Highsun. After visiting for a little bit one of the women said “I am looking to hire someone. My ship was pirated by some assholes flying this symbol (She holds up the symbol of the Cult of the Crushing Wave). Must we travel all the way to Waterdeep for help?”

Barikhol was quick to stand up and greet the ladies. “Me lases, have uh seat, let’s tulk.” The red head looked over to the blonde to see what she thought. The blonde took a look at the table and looked back and shrugged.

They approached the table and sat down. They introduced themselves at Teria and Sesa. They explained their ship was stolen on the Dessarin River. The heroes had to promise to return half the cargo from the ship, plus the ship, and they can keep the other half as payment. Once agreed they asked “Do you really think you can handle this job?”

Barikhol replied “How about give us a night to think it over, and you go and talk to the town’s people about what we can do.”

Teria said “We seal a deal a little differently where we are from.” Sesa waves down Marielye. When she comes over Sesa whispers something in her ear, Marielye nods, and goes back to retrieve shots. “This is from my family’s distillery.”

Everyone shot it back, and it hit them hard. It was probably, if not the best, one of the best whiskeys everyone ever tasted. Barikhol looked up at Teria and asked “I think you may want to try something from my 9 Hammers and a Keg Brewery.”

<I would like to talk about this more in the game and in notes. What is the name of Barikhol ’s 9 Hammers and a Keg Brewery ? What is the name of the ale? Is it ale? Let’s build this since it is a built location that keeps getting referenced.>

The heroes had fun that night. Everyone was drinking, music was playing, people were dancing, Barikhol and Teria may have snuck off at some point, and everyone had legitimate fun. For a splitting moment one could forget that the lands were plagued with evil occultist kidnapping people into slavery, killing merchants for loot, robbing and burning villages, and more. The heroes deserved this moment. They do not get too many of these. So they lived this like it was their last. Because, well you never know.

The next morning the heroes were feeling refreshed and enjoying their breakfast (at roughly 10:00AM). They agreed to Teria and Sesa to get their ship back. The party agreed they needed money and this was a good job. The bonus was it was also part of the mission they set off on. Teria and Sesa decided not to travel on to Waterdeep.

While they were finishing their meal a boy known as Braelen walks in. “Armond?” he asks approaching the table.

Armond turned to the child and remembered him. “Braelen, what can I do for you?”

“Armond there is a man on the south end of town wanting to speak with you.” He replied. The boy looked nervous and scurried off.

The heroes all took a glance at each other, shrugged, grabbed their stuff, and headed to the edge of town.

Harburk was standing there with his arms crossed looking at the visitor standing about 200 feet from the edge of town. They had to speak up to hear one another, but their voices carried well enough. “Are you Armond of the Heroes of Red Larch?” he says. Now that everyone has gotten a closer look, this man is standing with two creatures, which appear to be zombies, chained to him.

“I am.” Armond replied, “Who may you be?”

“My name is Imusek, father of Oreioth, he was also known as the Lord of Lance Rock. I believe you sent this.” He says holding up one of the flyers that Armond had Endrith put together.

“OK, you found me, what do you want?” Armond said to the necromancer.

“I come only asking for a possession he held that was never his to begin with. I also request to know where his body is.” Imusek replied.

Armond thinks and realizes he threw the body into the quarry. He is about to speak up when Harburk shouted “The body is buried south of here.” Harburk gives a landmark so the necromancer can find him. Armond looks over at Harburk and he gives Armond a little side smirk.

“Thank you. The item I am looking for is known as The Dagger of Velsharron. I would like that back please.” He says. The necromancer speaks with an annoying high voice, like his son.

“Unfortunately we do not have that item. We know who took it.” Armond replied.

“Will you retrieve it for me? That dagger in the wrong hands can do terrible things.” Imusek said.

“Like what?” Grimble asked.

“You don’t question the great Imusek, I shall rip…” Imusek thought, but said “The dagger holds many properties. It can summon the soul of long ago and place it in a young man’s body.”

The heroes didn’t seemed to be phased by this idea. Imusek thought that a man of the cloth would have a great problem with this. Souls should move on, to take death away from someone should be cruel.

“How about this.” Armond said, “You help us get it back and it’s yours.”

“Like hell I will travel with you filthy lot…” Imusek thought, but decided to say “Surely your paladin may have a problem with this.”

“I don’t want to travel with you either, but if it is for the greater good, I will consider it.” Grimble said.

“Interesting.” Imusek thought. “I shall think about it, I will need a tenday. I will return to this spot.”

Imusek walked away.

{Cut Scene}

Tyelknowle steps off a wagon that is heading northeast to Silverymoon. He walks into the Helm at Highsun and finds the rest of his companions discussing their next move over lunch.

{/Cut Scene}

Child Topics

Game 15

Game 14 | Home | Game Notes | Game 12&13

Finding Ourselves

Overview

Theme or Threat: Theme

Type: Soft

Barikhol, Armond, and Rowena have recently been captured and tortured for over 5 months. They all have histories that many adventures do. Most adventurers do not take the call under good times. For many something bad has to happen. They are lucky if it is just one thing.

In this Theme we will be exploring these three heroes journey back to finding their center. They will be tempted to veer off course, but hopefully, together, they can find the strength to raise themselves back up to be the heroes that the citizens of Red Larch know them to be.

This theme also encompases Tyelknowle and Grimble.

Tyelknowle is struggling with returning to the Mud-Blood family or continuing his quest with his fellow Heroes of Red Larch.

Grimble is still deciding if working with these adventurers will help him with his goals.

Impending Doom

Player Theory: Rowena : Something is going wrong with her spirit fox.
Barikhol : He is losing center and focus.
Armond : He is questioning if he is going to lose himself to the darkness.
Tyelknowle : He is struggling with returning to the Mud-Blood family or continuing his quest with his fellow Heroes of Red Larch .
Grimble : He is still deciding if working with these adventurers will help him with his goals.

Real Doom: Rowena : Her wild spirit will die

Barikhol: He will lose center and his monk abilities will cease

Armond: He will lose connection to his demon and his demon will think Armond is breaking his deal.

End Doom:: Rowena : This will end when she allows her wild magic to run free during a major confrontation.

Barikhol: This will end when Barikhol rides the worm.

Armond: will have a confrontation with his demon. His demon will turn off his powers, but Armond will get powers from a new source. They will be the same (unless he wants to stat change), but fundamentally different. Killing his demon will end this condition, but fundamentally change everything about Armond.

Rewards:: Rowena : In the end she will get a pet. Her Fox spirit can take form by using Odert or Rowena ’s soul and leave her body. Rowena will have connection to it at all times.

Barikhol:

Armond:

Tyelknowle: He made his decision to come back after his trip to Waterdeep. But fate had a different decision for him and he returned to waterdeep.

Rowena discovered what was hurting her spirit fox. She allowed the wild magic to flow.

Barikhol remembered who he was and was able to ride the Remorhaz. He is now a monk of the yellow rose.

Moments

Barikhol: had a moment where Grimble was stressing when a conversation with Grimble was happening. Barikhol had thoughts of attacking and maybe worse to Grimble, but something stopped him at the last minute. Barikhol went for a walk and found himself at their room. He found a note from Rowena.

Barikhol is having anger issues. He smashed a bugbear in the face over and over with a mace.

Rowena: Rowena's magic is getting out of control she was afraid of endangering the party so she packed up and went out to follow her spirit.

Armond requested a Necromancer, Imusek, come with the group to help them with the Sacred Stone Monastery. This is not an agreed move with the group

Events

Rowena: will need to feel like letting her Wild Magic out is hurting her spirit, but it is a misunderstanding. Her spirit needs to run free so it can heal. By it only getting out in spirts it is getting sick.

Rowena: She will find it harder and harder to track down her spirit. Her ears will slowly turn more halfelf like. Her red hair will start turning brown.

Barikhol: will feel his abilities weaken. When he fails an ability roll we will role play that he is off centered.

Barikhol: will also have dreams of being back with Larrakh and in that final moment, he will look up to see his master Oboku watch him and his face fill with heartache.

Armond: He will have that feeling like if the power goes out. There is always a constant buzz, but now it is gone.

Armond: When Armond fails a spell roll we will roleplay the spell fizzles. He is losing his connection to the Demon.

The Demon will tell Armond that Barikhol is making him weak. Take him out.

Armond's Demon | Home | Themes and Threats | Next

Armond Backstory

Stories

Backstory

As a young child of peasant serfs, life was not all fun and games. From the time that Armond could walk, he was working the fields helping out his folks. Most of the week he tended to the lord's fields; plowing, seeding, fixing fences, or anything to keep the young serf busy. The other couple of days he attend his family's meager plot of land to provide food for his family and produce to sell at the market. One day while clearing a section of field of rocks, a young lord was passing by and noticed that Armond was diligently removing rocks while other children played. This dedication to his work at such a young age impressed the young lord. Lord Arthuris DeLark decide to pay the young serf's parents for their loss as Armond was now to serve as the lord's page/stable boy. Lord Arthuris gave Armond the rest of the day to get what little belongs he owned and say his goodbyes as he most likely would never see his parents again.

 Now as a page/stable boy Armond duties were no less tedious than he had been before, but just a different skill set. His main duties were to clean the horse stalls, maintain the horses, and help the master carpenter make repairs. Several years had pass and Armond had grown into a strong lad from all the manual labor. During his free time he would watch the house guard train and every once in a while Squire Fenner would partake in the exercises. When no one was looking Armond would go behind the stables and practice what he saw. Unbeknownst to Armond , Lord Arthuris had seen him several times practice what he could remember. One day as Armond was in the middle of his routine he was startled by Arthuris's approach, having seen Armond master the basic moves that he had witness, Lord Arthuris asked if he would like to formal train with the guard. As Armond eagerly accepted the lord's offer Lord Arthuris informed him that his duties came first and foremost and any slack in duties would result in disciplinary actions. Well Armond never slack in duties nor training. His dedication to training had afforded him with the prowess to best any man other than the swordmaster, Fenner, or Arthuris; for they had studied noble swordsmanship.

 During his time at Lord Arthuris's keep Armond had befriend many but no more so than Fenner. Fenner was the nephew of Arthuris and had been sent to become an apprentice squire under Arthuris in order to one day become a Knight. Fenner had all the makings to become a great knight. He easily understood social and political ethos, master of several languages, and was on his way to becoming a master swordsman. A little time after Armond join the guard training sessions, Fenner started taking a liking to him. Seeing a lot of himself in Armond , he decided to teach Armond the fine points of a noble's education; teaching him of military tactics and strategy as well as the noble sword play. As time went by the two of them grew close as brothers. When Armond was around seventeen years of age, the lord informed him that some of the guard, Fenner and Armond himself would be leaving to join the King's Purple Dragons for the King had taxed his vassals with orders for soldiers. Lord Autheris expressed his fondness for Armond and has come to regard him as a member of his family. Within the week the soldiers, including Armond and Fenner, left for the Capital.

  On the road to the Capital Fenner and Armond ran into a little trouble. While passing through a small village they saw a fire. As they rushed up to lend aid, they saw the village was under attack by goblins. They jumped into action and fought off these vile creatures, but unfortunately Armond and Fenner were too late. As they turned a corner the heroes notice a wagon was rushing away driven by a person that could have been human with dark red skin. There were two goblins looking back at the village and Armond could make out maybe 3 bodies in the back. The wagon was too far away for Armond and Fenner to catchup so they did all they could by helping to put out the flames.

While they were burning the bodies of the goblins Armond noticed that one of them had a branding on his upper leg that was covered with cloth before. It looks like a bowl and it looked new.

The village thanked the heroes and gave them food, drink, and a place to sleep for the night before they were on their way again the next day.

Upon arriving in the Capital, Suzail, the new recruits had to go through a rigorous evaluation to determine their skills. All of Lord Arturis's troop attain the highest level thanks in part to their master swordsman's teachings. Fenner and Armond advanced through the ranks in a relatively quick time with Fenner earning the rank of Swordcaptian (Lieutenant) and Armond Swordmajor (Sergeant Major) within 5-6 years. The higher ups took notice and assigned them into the Elite Guard. As elite guards their duty was to escort visiting nobles through the kingdom of Cormyr.

One fateful day while traveling from the border of the Dalelands south along the Stonelands to Gnoll's pass, the noble's caravan was ambushed by a gang of ogres (The Teeth, mercenaries). These ogres are different than the types read about in books. Most ogres couldn't be bothered with fine weapons and armor, but some of these ogres had well-constructed weapons and armor made of stone. It seemed to be only given to the 'leaders' of the ogre group (for lack of a better term). The group held their own, as well as any monster hunter could, but as the heat of battle raged on, Armond 's foolhardiness got the best of him and he, disobeying orders, charged after the fleeing ogres leaving very few soldiers to guard the caravan. When Armond came to his senses and hurried back he was horrified by the sight. A small second wave of ogres had attack the caravan from behind and slaughter the remaining soldiers. Only Fenner had managed to kill and fend them off until the war-chief torn through him with his great spear as Armond approached. Smiling with glee as he backed off, the war-chief had his men ignite the royal carriage ablaze and cause a landslide that pushed the royal carriage down the hill and mostly buried it as they scampered off with the treasure of the noble family on the other side where the survivors of the attack could not reach . Armond could hear screams of agony from within the carriage and fought through the flames to get to them but there was nothing that could be done, the flames were too intense. After he gave up trying to help the noble family Armond ran to Fenner side. As Fenner lay dying in his arms, Armond promised always to think first before acting as not to ever cause others such pain.

After Armond and the remaining soldiers of the company returned back to the garrison and Armond gave a full report of what happen; after words the wounded got medical care including Armond , for the fire had burned if left arm and back. Some days later Armond was call to the Constal (Colonel) for debriefing, During the debrief, Armond was informed that due to his actions he would be stripped of all rank, be administered administrative punishment, all land/wealth seized to pay restitution for the lives lost then exile from within the borders of Cormyr. As soon as the debriefing was over they took Armond to the stocks were they stripped him of his armor and administered 15 lashings. While still bleed and half conscious, they shacked him and loaded him in to a wagon and shipped him out of the realm to the city Iriaebor. Once they neared the city they un-sacked Armond and through him out of the wagon into the dirt. With no money, no food, and no shelter Armond slowly and drudgingly made his way to Iriaebor.

Leokas Backstory | Home | Character Backstories | Barikhol Backstory

Grimble Collaborative Adventure

Stories

Heroes:: Grimble , Tyelknowle , Armond

During one of his first adventures after leaving his mountain home, Grimble was traveling to the city of Waterdeep where he might learn of any threats or conspiracies that may pose a threat to his clan or his Dwarven way of life. On the road to Waterdeep he encountered a human merchant being harassed by a small band of brigands. The brigands appeared to be ill-equipped, only having small knives and a single light crossbow amongst them. While this seemingly posed no threat to the Dwarves (there were only three of them), Grimble was bored from travelling and eagerly inserted himself into proceedings.

“Me-thinks you babbling, lice-ridden, kobold spawn should press on somewhere else or ye’ll be picking yer arses off the ground.”

The ruffians, thinking they were being addressed by another human, spun around with hatred in their eyes, but when they were confronted by a sturdy dwarf in armor carrying a large hammer the fire in their eyes went out and their faces paled. Even with their superior numbers and a crossbow, they immediately knew they were out-classed and had little chance of coming out a fight without any permanent damage. To Grimble’s great disappointment, the bandits retreated down the road a little way before disappearing into the surrounding foliage with great haste. The merchant, thrilled beyond measure with how things worked out, begged Grimble to accompany him to Waterdeep and offered a large sum of money for protection. Grimble declined the pay, but agreed to accompany the merchant on his way…besides, he was tired of walking and welcomed the opportunity to ride on the wagon. As they traveled and spoke, Grimble learned that the merchant was on his way to Waterdeep to sell arms and armor. His wares were stored in locked, iron-bound trunks in the wagon. The merchant, eager to please his savior, boasted that his wares were of the finest Dwarven make. Suspicious, Grimble proceeded to ask him questions concerning his wares, such as who the armorer was, from what clan did he hail, and how he came by these items. The merchant wasn’t an overly smart man and was unable to provide any decent answer to many of the questions posed by Grimble. Believing the merchant was either a liar or a thief, Grimble became angry and was loosening his hammer from its thong when a voice called out from in front of the stopped wagon.

“Hello, good Sirs! What takes thee to Waterdeep?”

Looking, Grimble saw a knife-eared elf (Tyelknowle) standing before them, hands on his hips and a wry smile on his face.

The caravan driver slowed to a stop eyeing the elf suspiciously.

"Do I know you elf?" He asked, his tone suggesting he did.

"I doubt it. I was traveling from Silverymoon to Cormyr by way of Waterdeep but my horse and supplies disappeared, likely stolen I'm sad to say. I have been walking the last day or so hoping to meet a friendly caravan to wagon. I have a few silver still, but can pay more once I get to Waterdeep. I have contacts there."

"Why were you traveling that way? Are you some merchant?" The driver's eyes lit up at the sound of money. Grimble thought about the story, which sounded pathetic, and decided it was well rehearsed. He couldn't see any flaws in it, but the elf deserved more watching, being an elf and all.

The driver took 7 silver and agreed to 2 more gold and agreed to share his meals. They had 2 more nights travel by wagon. The elf hopped in the back and proceeded to doze off. Grimble now had to watch two people.

The conversation died down among them till that night when they discussed keeping watch. The elf offered to keep middle watch and the driver said he was an early riser to he would keep third watch. This left Grimble with first watch. That didn't sit too well with him, but he had no real good reason to argue. After a lite supper the other two bedded down. Just about midnight Grimble woke up the elf. In the fire light something seemed different about him. He was no longer as light skinned or slim built, even his hair seemed to change in color and length.

"My friend, I assume by your holy symbol that you are a man of faith. I am a faithful of Tymora." The elf moved closer and whispered, "I have been tracking a threat to travelers to this road. What I've been able to discern is that a merchant has been traveling this road and kidnapping people. Anyone from bandits to travelers. And in groups smaller than 4. I'm not sure how he does it, and my contacts say it is a single person in a wagon with a heavy load. I've been waiting for 6 days and I've seen this wagon pass twice before both times with a different passenger. You are the third. I disguised myself so he didn't recognize me. Please, you must help me. I don't know how he does it or where he takes them, but there is something strange here."

Grimble could tell this was more truth than the elf had spoken since they met. It did explain the mans strange answers but the story seemed crazy.

"How do I know YOU aren't the threat?" Grimble asked loosing his weapon.

"For one, why would I tell you the story when I could have simply waited for you to sleep? Second, if you can conceive of a way to test me, I will submit, but I beg you keep it quite. We must act before he knows." The elf seemed genuinely concerned, but that could be for any number of reasons. Grimbly was a dwarf of action and this bespoke subterfuge. The elf, taller and darker skinned then any elf Grimble had seen (but not as dark as a Drow) was keeping a steady eye on the merchant who seemed to be snoring away.

"I don't know what you expect or why, but I'm willing to wake up before you wake the merchant. Than I'll keep a secret watch to see what he does. I warn you, DON'T cross me." Grimble found the whole affair distasteful but something about the elf's concern and the merchant's strange mannerisms had him on edge.

"Fair enough. I will trust you friend. I am Tyelknowle , but you may call me Ty for short. If something does happen to me and you survive, please let anyone at the temple of Tymora in Waterdeep know what happened."

Grimble had a hard time going back to sleep, but he must of because Ty was gently shaking him awake again. The elf had his finger to his lips in a sign of silence. Gimble narrowed his eyes then adjusted himself so he could keep a better, more secretive watch on the merchant, and Ty (just in case). He muttered as Ty chanted some words holding his holy symbol and he seemed to flow back into the same elf they had met on the road. He then woke the merchant, keeping Grimble behind him making it easier for Grimble to watch unnoticed.

"Thank you good elf. If you are interested, I have some wares. I was going to share them with the dwarf but he is uninterested in elven weapons and armor. I would be happy to show you." The merchant moved quietly towards the wagon. Elf ware? What was this merchant playing at, did he suspect people would be so dumb as to not tell where good equipment came from?

"Thank you but no. I'm afraid I couldn't carry anything and you know I have little money currently." The elf seemed a little taken aback but the merchant had moved to one of the locked boxes.

"Nonsense, come take a peak. Even if you can't afford it now perhaps it will wet your appetite." The merchants words sounded strange and his shadow seemed a little more bulky than he recalled.

"Oops, it looks like a couple of my chest have been opened. What will I do?" Grimble was sure something was amiss, but he didn't know what. He kept his head down as Ty was making his way towards the fire. Ty suddenly drew a dagger and flung it at Grimble … No, above him. He heard a hiss.

"Awake! We are being attacked!" Ty was yelling and pulled two more daggers, seemingly from nowhere. Grimble was already on his feet but he realized there was slithering all around the camp. A glance at the merchant showed he had opened another box making it three total. So, the elf had been right. Looks like he would owe him a drink, if the City of Bones had a tavern in it. The two stood back to back...

As Ty and Grimble glanced back into the night they counted three mammoth serpents, long as a wagon and thicker than a dwarf's leg, circling the camp. One of the serpent had a nasty gash on its underside where Ty's dagger made purchase. Grimble readied his shield with hammer poised above his head. A glint from Ty's hand sent two more daggers racing towards another serpent, finding home in its throat and face. As it reeled back in agony, Grimble followed up with a titanic blow against its head, crushing its skull with ease.

Quick as lightning, the other serpent struck a Grimble but with his battle hardened prowess was at the ready with his shield to block the attack. Suddenly Ty could make out what could only be described as serpent speech coming from the Merchant, which seemed to be directing the serpents. (So my Harry Potter game had the players in the tavern. Now my DnD game has parseltongue.) As Ty focused more on the shadowy figure of the merchant he could notice that the Merchant seem to have grown and was covered in scaly patches.

With another load crack, Grimble sent another serpent to meet its fate. Without warning the Merchant lunged at Ty projecting a puff of noxious gas from his palm. Ty fell to a knee choking on the noxious gas trying not to succumb to it poisons effects. Out of the night came a harrowing battle cry; as a chain mail clad warrior came rushing into the camp masterfully spinning about his mass glaive. Seeing that the elf was in trouble the warrior placed himself between the Merchant and the elf.

The Merchant, with a low grumble hiss, laughed as he drew his blades. He attacked with the wild fury of a whirling dervish. The warrior defend every slash, slice and stab that came at him returning with his own frantic strikes. Ty push through the poisons effect to join the fight with warrior and merchant. It seem like Ty and the warrior had fought together like train companions, dodging and weaving around each other while striking at the merchant. This combo was just too great for the merchant to take on, receiving cuts and stabs repeatedly.

From behind Grimble yells, “duck!” As Ty and the warrior do so, the three massive serpent goes flying over their head right into the merchant knocking him down to the ground. Without missing a beat Ty was right on the merchant with blade to his throat.

"Surrender or die", barked Ty. Knowing he was out matched, the merchant surrendered. After tying him up, Ty again fell to his knee trying to fight off the poison. The warrior said he can help and gave Ty an antitoxin vial.

The warrior introduced him elf as Armond Creed. "I was paid to patrol the trade roads to find the culprit or culprits responsible for kidnapping small groups of travelers. It was just dumb luck find you guys in time. All I had to go on was the ramblings of a woman who managed to get away." "I would be more than willing to share the bounty with both of you."

Barikhol Collaborative Adventure | Home | Character Collaborative Adventures | Rowena Collaborative Adventure

Rowena Collaborative Adventure

Stories

Heroes:: Rowena (Black and light blue), Barikhol (Blue), Tyelknowle (green), Storyteller (red)

Rowena kicked her feet lazily back and forth as they dangled inches above the gravelly road. The back of the wagon she sat in bumped along, jostling her lightly as the caravan sauntered slowly towards its next checkpoint. She casually brushed a displaced lock of her silvering hair behind her softly pointed ear, then pulled her pack into her lap to rummage around for something. Humming quietly to herself, she seemed to have found what she was looking for, but a sudden jolt caused her to drop it back in the pack; she barely caught herself from tumbling into the road. The wagon had stopped abruptly, the wheel having fallen into an inconspicuous rut which seemed to have cracked the axle. Shouts and curses arose from the front of the caravan as people wandered over to take a look at the damage.

The clatter of horse's hooves and the shouts of men echoed almost as loudly as the thundering in Barikhol 's head. The last batch of ale had been potent enough that he felt as if an army of dwarves was working a forge inside his skull.

As he opened his eyes, he found leaves closing in around him. "Odd" he thought, why had he woken up in a bush? The last thing he remembered was drinking his latest brew while walking towards town to resupply. Potent indeed.

The sound of shouting and cursing grew louder, and finally Barikhol could stand it no more. What were these people doing, running a caravan by his bush?! He crawled out from under the low hanging shrubs, and there was indeed a caravan. It looked like one of the wagons had broken down, and was leaning at an odd angle.

He approached the caravan to see what the problem was, and approached a young elf maid. She told Barikhol that the wagon had landed in a rut and something had snapped. Being a dwarf, and having the mechanical aptitude and craftiness of his race, Barikhol climbed under the wagon to take a look.

The axle had broken in half, but only a part of the diameter was splintered. The other part had clean saw marks, which had served to weaken the axle. It was enough to get the wagon far from town on the rough roads before it splintered. Why would someone sabotage a wagon so it broke down in the wild? This was surely no day for a hangover.

Joclyn had made excellent time chasing after the caravan and Tyelknowle knew he had to hurry if he was going to help stop Joclyn from making a terrible decision . Nicoli had been more than irate, a member of the Mud Blood , Joclyn , working with common highwaymen was bad enough, but sabotaging wagons on the road was horrible business that would come back to haunt everyone. Too much attention, too many blatant robberies, too much death and we would be lucky if just local authorities showed up. More likely adventurers looking for a bounty or just loot and everyone on the road would be suspect and targets. Nicoli rammed this point into Tyelknowle and he knew she was right.

Tyelknowle spotted the ambush from behind moving up the game trail. Joclyn would be down low ready to confuse the worst of the fighters. As a tiefling, she had a knack for magic and loved showing up more “muscle types” as she put it.

The wagon had been stopped for only a couple of minutes and some dwarf had bent down to crawl underneath. The attack would happen soon, at the worst possible time. The young elf was less stealthy than normal. He ran the risk of being confused for one of the bandits, but he had to get… “NOW! Your goods or your lives!” a bandit cried out. It was too late Ty thought .

Tyelknowle saw at least 20 men jump from both sides of the road. A gang that big had to hit a lot of targets or else not enough got paid and that meant internal fighting. It also meant they weren’t usually very well trained or else they would have simply relied on mercenary work, much more profitable and stable. He happened to be only a few feet from one of the archers so he slipped out his rapier and slipped it up the left side, just above the hip crossing to the upper right, puncturing at least one lung and all sorts of other organs that he was sure were needed. There was more yelling, muffled, the dwarf under the wagon hadn’t been surprised and maybe that was enough for the others to at least get a weapon out or run. Running was always better in this situation .

Ty couldn’t see clearly, so he moved closer to another waiting archer. This archer he stabbed just under the right lower ribs and up. Closer than he liked, but just as effective. The bandits were confident and thus not aware that two of their number had been dropped before the fight had truly started. There was always a few seconds where most bandits watched to see if their prey would fight or flee. Tyelknowle would not be good in a straight up fight, and his goal was the tiefling. He stabbed down the spine of a third bandit who looked ready to charge and found himself at the edge of the road.

The targets had not ran, but they seemed a bit confused. There were at least two other people making a ruckus on the other side and nobody seemed sure what was happening. At the same time he spotted Joclyn so did the dwarf (still under the wagon). Tyelknowle , seeing some of the caravans horses, was not about to rob anyone but he had to get her out of here and quickly. Also, how much longer could he remain unseen by both sides? As long as he could stop his adopted sister, maybe they had someone he that could help stop all this, maybe; Damn his luck...

Joclyn was preparing to cast one of her fog spells, which would have been the advantage the bandits needed to wipe out the caravan. Barikhol , seeing all of this encounter from under his wagon and yelled out “young elf maid, help him!” while nodding toward the rogue elf quietly taking out highwaymen and trying to make his way to the tiefling. Barikhol threw his wrench at Joclyn breaking her concentration on the fog.

Startled by a garbled cry of, “Now! You’re good for a prize!” Rowena stepped out from behind the wagon to see several highwaymen initiates charging at the caravan. Leading the charge was a bizarre looking… woman?

Oh, a tiefling. How interesting. Rowena had time to muse, before throwing forward her arms to send a spell at the marauders and halt their attack.

Sleep. Sleep sleep sleep sleep…. She bit her lip in concentration. Hadn’t quite gotten the hang of this one, yet…

Suddenly, a swarm of flumphs appeared around her. Oh. Not quite what I was going for… The floating creatures scattered, fleeing in terror.

Seeing a swarm of floating jellyfish creatures heading straight for them, the startled highwaymen broke off their charge in confusion. “Someone has summoned demons from another plane!” When the lead flumph reached the bandits, it shot out a foul smelling spray, dousing the devilish looking woman in a disgusting smelling liquid. Several of her comrades began hacking and gagging. As they backed away from their fallen, fetid friend, the rest of the flumphs continued to rush past the bandits. Rowena ran up to the downed bandit, who seemed to have been completely disoriented.

Sleep! Rowena ’s thoughts raged, and the tiefling fell over, unconscious. Rowena ’s gaze lifted from the woman laying at her feet to stare wistfully at the retreating pack of flumphs. Oh well. Maybe I’ll catch one next time…

As Rowena bent down check the tiefling’s condition, she slowly realized that she was not alone. “You didn’t kill her. Thank you for that. She’s just… misguided,” said a man’s voice next to her. Rowena looked up to see another highwaymen, his hand casually resting on the hilt of his sword.

“Well,” Rowena said nervously, eyeing the man, “I try to make that more of a last resort…”

“The name is Tyelknowle .” He began rummaging through his pack, searching for something.

“ Rowena .” She responded, trying to peer at what he was looking for. “What are you doing…?”

Tyelknowle produced a rope from his pack and began tying up the tiefling. “Looking for this.”

“Oh. I’m working on the incarcerous spell. My grandmother told me a story and their wizards used it. It would have been pretty helpful right now.” Footsteps behind her caused Rowena to turn and miss the elf’s confused look.

“Ereything a’right here, lass?” the bush-dwarf growled.

“Yep! Tyelknowle is tying up his buddy here. Who are you, by the by?” Rowena smiled.

“ Barikhol . Charmed.” He said, eyeing over the elf.

“Well, then. Shall we get back to fixing that wheel?”

“You’re just gonna let this devilwoman walk?”

“Well, not exactly. She’ll be asleep for a bit longer, so I don’t think she’ll be walking anywhere…”

Tyelknowle unsheathed his sword and stepped in front of the tiefling. “Please. Let me take her. My guild will ensure she meets just punishment.”

“Now now,” Rowena hedged, “No need to swing that pointy thing around. And I don’t mean your ears. But you had better get going before the caravan leader finds you.

As Tyelknowle gets up to take his sister out of here he whispers "Thank you" and turns around with his sisters arm over his shoulder starts heading towards the woods.

Suddenly, a hand grabs his arm firmly and he spins around ready for whatever comes at him. Tyelknowle was a little surprised to see Rowena stopping him. "Your sister is the cause of many people getting injured. If any of them died today she would not be leaving here. Promise me she will be properly dealt with."

Tyelknowle could see Rowena was vacillating with her decision on letting them go. "I will, promise." he told her.

Rowena must have decided to believe him because she let them go.

Grimble Collaborative Adventure | Home | Character Collaborative Adventures | Tyelknowle Collaborative Adventure

Barikhol Backstory

Stories

Barikhol was born in Mithiril Hall to Barik and Gwanwyn Stoutale . Gwanwyn died during childbirth, as giving birth to a dwarf is akin to pushing out a boulder, and it oft times ended badly.

Barikhol grew up like other dwarves, learning the basics of combat with the hammer and axe just like all dwarves and enjoyed his training.  He liked to fight, and actually had plenty of opportunities, due to his father’s less than sterling reputation.

Barik was a brewer, which is usually a well-respected trade for a dwarf.  The problem was that Barik wasn’t a very good brewer, and most of his ales were sold as “dares” between friends, or as punishment for lost bets.  So, dwarven children, as all children, ridiculed Barikhol .  They called him things like “badale” and referred to him as “goblin piss” because the only thing that his father made was poor tasting spirits, and obviously his father had made him.  So, he enjoyed crunching other’s noses under his fists, and got very good at it.  Before long, any ridicule was done out of Barikhol ’s earshot.

Dwarven sons tend to take up the trade of their fathers, and this often goes back several generations.  As such Barikhol was to be a brewer (which he didn’t find very attractive, giving the reputation of his father).  During his studies, Barikhol found a note in a brewer’s book that had been handed down for generations.  The note was a recipe for Fire Mead, which was written by his great, great grandfather.  The recipe compared the Fire Mead to the dwarven stout that is so loved by all of the small folk, but the bite would make a red dragon’s eyes water.  One of the main ingredients was dragon peppers, which were hard to come by in Mithiril Hall, and grew only in the Anaroch Desert.   Barikhol told his father about the discovery, and since the Stoutale Tavern had no business to speak of, they were on the road the next day.

The travel was easy in his father’s wagon, and they enjoyed the travel together; it was a father and son adventure.  Until the orcs attacked.

Barikhol will never forget these filthy orcs. They wore a distinct stony armor. Most orc are costumed to basically go without armor. Some orcs will tie different pieces of armor, shields, and random pieces of metal together to give them some kind of protection. These orcs seemed to have armor tailored for them out of stone.

They came screaming out of the trees on both sides of the small trail. They killed the horses pulling the wagon first; presumably so the dwarfs could not flee.  Barik was no fighter, but leapt in front of his son to protect him.  He died quickly, with a sword thrust to the chest.   Barikhol did his best to kill the orcs, but there were many and he was young.  He did manage a satisfying punch to an orc’s face and felt bones give under the weight of his blow.  Then the spear pierced his back, high on the shoulder.   Barikhol knew he must flee or die.

The orcs did not run him down, and seemed more interested in what dwarves were carrying in the wagon.  Dumb, smelly orcs probably thought it was gold and weapons.   Barikhol was sure all orcs thought dwarves did nothing but smith and mine.

After running several miles bleeding (not to mention a damned spear sticking out of his back) Barikhol left the road and removed the spear.  That was the last he remembered for some time.  When he awoke, he trudged back to the wagon to bury the remains of his father, only to find the body gone, and the wagon wrecked.  Apparently brewing supplies didn’t interest the stupid beasts.   Barikhol scavenged what supplies he could and set up camp in a small clearing.

A terrible thought occurred to him; he didn’t know how to get back to Mithril Hall!  After panicking for a few moments, he decided that it didn’t matter, as he had no friends there, and it had always been a place of ridicule for him.  This clearing in the forest was as good a place as any.  He set up a small distillery, and there he stayed, surviving and brewing meads and ales, not far from a small road.  Occasionally, a traveler would pass and share a mug of ale, food and news with Barikhol .

In a nearby town lived this group of four builders. They were always traveling for work. This was good business for Barikhol because every time they were on their way somewhere they would stop by, have a few drinks, and buy a barrel for the road. When they would return, they would tell Barikhol that they told everyone where they bought this ale and buy a few more drinks.

They were fun to have in the tavern and the other customers loved them. One day they did their customary stop to get some drinks and buy a barrel for the road. They drank, sang, and played games with other patrons. On their way out they said 'we will see you in a month and you better have something new for us'. A month passed and they never showed up. Barikhol never heard from these four again.

Oboku was one such traveler.   Oboku was a monk from the Monastery of the yellow rose.  He was sent as an emissary to Waterdeep to help verify the lineage of a minor noble from Vassa.   Oboku was travelling back to the monastery and shared with Barikhol 's camp one night.  The two became fast friends.   Barikhol told Oboku of his father's death, and his inability to stop the orcs.  If only he had been stronger, a better fighter, his father may still be alive.

Oboku gave Barikhol a small demonstration of the Way of Flowers martial art (the man snapped a small tree with a kick!).  That is all Barikhol needed, and he asked Oboku if he could go to the monastery with him and study.

Many years passed for Barikhol at the monastery.  In the beginning, Barikhol worked for most of the day doing menial tasks and very little else.  He was taught of the monastery’s deity, Ilmater, the god of endurance.  This god made so much sense to him as he endured much hardship in his early life.

After a time, Master Oboku began to train Barikhol in the studies of the Way of Flowers.   Barikhol found his training most difficult. His stocky Dwarf body did not cooperate with the flowing flowery style.  Upon discussing this with Oboku , the suggestion was made to train in the 9 Hammer style.  The 9 Hammer Style truly fit Barikhol ; it’s straightforward heavy punches and short fast kicks suited the stocky dwarf well.

Oboku was very memorable. He is the first human you probably have meet to have a light blue skin. He never talked about it, but when his emotions would take the better of him nature seemed to react with him. The wind would blow open doors in rage or he would manage to stay cool on the warmest of summer days. If ever asked he would shrug it off and blame coincidence or say he likes the heat.

Years passed, and Barikhol ’s training was complete.  He was sent out into the wide world to seek his enlightenment, and be among the people.  However, he has promised to return to the Monastery of the Yellow Rose to finish his initiation and “Ride the Remorhaz” to become a Master of Dragons.

Armond Backstory | Home | Character Backstories | Grimble Backstory

Grimble Backstory

Stories

Grimble is a mountain (shield) dwarf born into Clan Battlehammer. His father was a well-known brew master throughout the kingdom. His excellent beers and ales were attributed the fact that the yeast he used was always blessed (for a cost) by a priest of the god Dumathoin. From an early age, Grimble took an interest in the fine art of brewing ale and learned as much about the craft as he could from his father. As he became older, and in holding with the name of his clan, he was taught the martial tradition of wielding the battle hammer and shield. Thanks to his father’s deeply rooted religious beliefs, Grimble was also a very pious dwarf. As soon as he was of age, he was indoctrinated into the church as a holy warrior and defender of the faith (paladin) in service of the Dwarven god of defense and vigilance, Gorm Gulthyn. This only strengthened his piety and resolve to the point of fanaticism when it comes to defending his clan and kingdom. Because of his unrelenting devotion to this cause, and the knowledge that external (to the clan/kingdom) forces sometimes threaten the sanctity of his ancestral way of life, he took an oath of vengeance against any who might threaten it and was charged by Gorm (the church) to travel the land and seek out those threats and destroy them.

Barikhol Backstory | Home | Character Backstories | Rowena Backstory

Tyelknowle Backstory

Stories

Clan name - Waa’nornoro [Wha - no - Nor - o]

*At age 10, several members of the clan, including Tyelknowle, his mother, father, and brother were captured by slavers.

* At age 18, brother dies in slavery.

* At age 24, Tyelknowle is sold to other slavers.

* At age 26, was being shipped to the Dagon Coast, the slavers got greedy and decided to attack a “Gypsy Caravan” mostly full of Half-elves and Tieflings. The slavers lost and the slaves were freed. Tyelknowle joins the “family”.

* At age 29 moves to Waterdeep to learn more about the “craft” but lives mostly on the street, begging, petty crime, and scrounging.

* At age 35, attempts a “big heist” on Jurras Bigglesworth, a wealthy merchant known to travel frequently. However, Jurras was home. Bigger surprise, Jurras is an influential lay member/supporter of the church of Tymora. Tyelknowle is offered to the chance to work off his debt/crime with the church. Tyelknowle accepts and becomes a member in training.

* At age 41, Tyelknowle makes a pilgrimage out of Waterdeep at the request of the Church (modern day).

Rowena Backstory | Home | Character Backstories | Josephus Backstory

Josephus Backstory

Stories

War.

War is hard on a person. There have been many people through the years that have lost themselves to it. It changes a being. Doesn’t matter if you’re a Human, Elf, Dwarf, Halfling, Man, Woman, Old, or Young. You will always come back a different person. Why does one ever choose this path? Sometimes, they don’t have a choice.

Josephus was a common man, working on a common farm, in a common town, with a common life. He was very easy going. Most of the time life was enjoyable. There was the occasional beast that would sneak on to the lands they had to deal with, but this wasn’t troubling to Josephus .

This was before the great flood. One morning there was lots of rain. Farm work was going to have to wait. The problem is the rain didn’t stop. It got really windy and dark too. After two days the place had major flooding. Josephus family had to evacuate to a nearby town. It wasn’t till they got there that they were informed that the lands are in the middle of a hurricane.

It got worst on the fourth day. The people that were staying in the town had to band together and repair buildings as parts of them were getting ripped apart. While out working on a roof Josephus was knocked off by a burst of wind. A female elf ranger nudged him before he hit the ground, breaking his fall. Josephus looked up at the adventuring party and said, “thanks.”

The adventuring party helped the townsfolk fix the damages and they got inside for warm meals and use of the fireplace. They told the townsfolk this isn’t a natural storm. A Water Cult and the Air Cult are at war and this is the backlash of their magic. The adventuring party is traveling to the Air Cult’s lands to try and stop them.

Two days later the Adventuring party came back. They were missing a member. It was the Elf Ranger who saved Josephus . Josephus never did get her name and would kick himself when he thought back to that moment. The adventuring party was unsuccessful at stopping the cults from fighting. It got worse the cults thought that the “mortals” were sending attackers to interfere in their affairs. They decided to attack the village as payback.

The village took a pounding from the storm now on day eight, many buildings have collapse, a few people have died, and the lands were so flooded they couldn’t travel. This is when the military came. The Air and Water cults struck the militants first, and the military defended. The battle broke inside the small town. The townspeople decided to act, and Josephus was one of them.

The battle was heavy and they took many losses. One loss will never leave Josephus mind. Isaac, Josephus father, was in a sword fight with two Water Cult attackers. He was not holding his own. Josephus took action and sliced away the air cults in front of him and took out one of the attackers on his father.

This freed up his father in being able to deal with the other water cult attackers and they stood there smiling at each other on their success. Out of nowhere an ice bolt came flying through Josephus father’s chest. As Isaac fell he said, “I am proud of you son.” He passed away quickly. This was Josephus first time experiencing death in the battle field. It haunted him, stuck with him, and it was a hard memory to forget.

A man by the Name of Talin came running up behind him. “Kid!” he yelled while taking out an air mage with a halberd. “You may greave tomorrow. I will greave with you, but right now there are others that really need your help!” This inspired Josephus and he picked up his sword and fought like he has never fought before.

The battle was epic and lasted hours. At the point when the military thought they finally won they heard a crashing of what sounded like trees. They looked to the outskirts of town and saw the woods shifting back and forth. Unknown to the town’s heroes a cultist released a dam and the river was heading straight for this town.

Crash! The waves hit the outskirts of town. The water was taller than any of the walls. The townsfolk ran for high ground, but many didn’t make it. People inside buildings had a slim chance of survival. If the building made it, they could try and make it towards the upper floors. But if the building didn’t survive the initial hit, those inside were lost.

Livia, a human female, made it out of a window on top of a building. The water was reaching her ankles. She started screaming for her son and husband. “ Josephus ! Isaac! Josephus ! Isaac!” Josephus made it over to her in the nick of time. Josephus was already planning on heading over to the building with his mother inside the moment the water hit. She was lucky the building didn’t give. They were not lucky for long.

The building, along with the rest of town, gave and everyone got swept away with town. It was a dangerous ride, and there were very few survivors. Josephus was able to hang on to his mother long enough for them to make it out. They finally stopped being pulled by the rushing wave and landed on a hill. Josephus holding onto his, still alive, mother. Thankful he didn’t lose everyone.

After this attack the cults left the rest of town to their destruction. The rain finally stopped, but it was almost a week before they could even return to town. Nothing was left. There were floating people, animals, beast, and buildings. The air and water cult took everything from them.

The town buried the bodies and said their prayers. Talin approached Josephus and said, “You are a good fighter. We really could use someone like you.” Josephus never really put much thought into the military before. “We need to put an end to these cultist before more towns end up like yours.”

Josephus and his mother were standing over his father’s (her husbands) grave. “Mom, I need to do something. I can’t let this happen to others. I can’t let them get away with this.”

Livia knew she would never be able to talk her son out of this. Once Josephus has made up his mind there was no stopping him. He reminded her of his father in that way. “Son,” Livia started, “Your father would be proud of you for what you’re going to do. He would ask you to think about one thing. Is your reason for this for others or yourself?” Josephus started to speak up but Livia stopped him, “This isn’t for me. This is for you to think about. I don’t need your answer. Only you do.”

Livia had family in a nearby village. Josephus and Talin took her there to get her settled in. They stayed a couple days to make sure she had everything she needed and it was also nice to rest up a little before their journey.

Jump ahead a few years. Josephus has settled in with the {Need name for Army} they were a special group of heroes that were seeking out cults that were destroying their world. Josephus fit in nicely with this group. They traveled and found many cult camps and created an end to them.

Josephus best friend was Talin. Talin worked with Josephus everyday as they were traveling to meet up with his military group. Talin was an excellent fighter. Years ahead of Josephus . Josephus knew he could learn so much from him. Talin enjoyed teaching him. Josephus was a quick learner, and having a friend to talk to made military life a lot easier.

Once day Josephus was out taking a piss when a little light flew by him quickly. Then again. And again. Josephus quickly wrapped up what he was doing and grabbed his sword (the other one) and readied himself. A little blue fairy landed on his sword and looked at him curiously. “What is your name? Mine is Leaf.”

Leaf became friends with both Josephus and Talin. The fairy taught Josephus how to cook. Josephus found he had a real talent at this. The Fairy would basically tell him what to do and Josephus would do it. Eventually they would have discussions about different types of foods and flavors. They experimented with different types of seasonings, meats, vegetables, and more. It was an awesome friendship. Talin found it amusing when everyone would be thanking Josephus for the excellent meal, and he could see Leaf hiding under his chef’s hat.

It was almost comical to watch them cook. “You’re stirring the wrong way. You must stir counter clockwise 3 times, clockwise once.”

“What does it matter?” Josephus would ask.

“Who is the master here?” Leaf would reply. Then would do something like bat a salt shaker out of Josephus hands. “Always test your ingredients! Sight, color, smell, taste, then pour.”

Wherever the army went Leaf would come along. No one in the army knew about Leaf, except of course Talin and Josephus . Leaf made them both promise to keep him a secret. When people found fairies they would try and catch them and make them do things. Leaf talked about how he was captured before. People that try to catch fairies make them promise to do as they wish and fairies after making this promise must do it. It is no way to live. Leaf never wishes to be in that kind of servitude again.

On a night that Josephus will never forget. He was preparing dinner for his mates, tomorrow there were plans of a big raid. The found a temple of a powerful air mage. Josephus also knew they were near a well-known fishing river. He knew Leaf would return in a couple hours. Leaf would leave them every now and then when he knew he was near family. This was one of the benefits Leaf saw when going with Josephus and Talin. He could travel safely to see others of his kind. Josephus knew if he could finish up with serving dinner Talin, Josephus , and Leaf could sneak off and go fishing. Except that never happened. Everyone got sick. Everyone in the camp.

It happened so quickly. They just started throwing up, coughing, and foaming at the mouth. They all died. The worst was Talin. Josephus ran up to him and held him as he was fading away. The last thing Talin asked him was "why?" 'Why?' is right, but also 'How?'. What killed them? Josephus knew he didn't put anything bad in the soup, but why was he the only one not affected? He ran back to the cooking corner. He started checking his ingredients and grabbed the nutmeg.

The label slid off. It wasn't nutmeg, but nightshade. He poured a little out on the counter. He looked at it, he checked the color, he smelled it, he took the smallest taste, and he quickly spit it out. It was nightshade, or at least Josephus was 99% sure it was. He looked around the camp. Everyone was dead and Josephus was the only one left alive. It would take a long time for Josephus to forgive himself of this. To this day he hasn’t. ‘Why didn’t I check the ingredients?’ he thought. Then he started thinking that he is in danger here. He then thought, ‘I need to get out of here.’ He grabbed his things and packed up and ran.

It wasn't till about 10 hours later that he realized he forgot something. Leaf! He forgot to meet with Leaf. Josephus thought 'I can't go back now.' and said aloud "Goodbye my friend. Goodbye to the both of you."

Tyelknowle Backstory | Home | Character Backstories | Next

Josephus Collaborative Adventure

Stories

Josephus, Wyer, Barikhol

Josephus , joined the army of a local warlord in search of adventure and glory.  Instead, he found himself pulling KP duty more often than not.  Not content to lead a military career peeling potatoes, he constantly worked to improve his martial prowess.  He worked tirelessly during his off-duty times to practice with anyone who was willing.  In addition to his military duties, he took time to learn the culinary arts so that he could provide his brothers-at-arms with the best camp food.  Because of his dedication and determination, he quickly advanced through the ranks of the kitchen staff and became the head chef.  He was deadly with a blade on and off the field and them men in the camp loved him.  One day, Josephus was preparing a delicious stew for his men.  Instead of grabbing the seasoning, he mistakenly grabbed some nightshade powder.  Many men died that day due to unknown causes.  Too late, Josephus realized his mistake.  He resigned from the military life and ventured out on his own in search of redemption.  He told no one his mistake and vowed to never do so.

Wyer stumbled through the woods, dazed and bleeding. That was stupid. Attacking those kobolds alone was not a good idea . Why didn't Wyer just invite Armond and Josephus ? But he had been hunting them, his quarry, for weeks and was exhausted, out of supplies, and just plain frustrated with the time wasted on false trails and missed opportunities to attack. So had charged in like the idiot he sometimes thought he was. Now he was going to die hungry, alone and wounded in these god forsaken woods. The kobolds had apparently also been out of food. Now it three days later and Wyer knows he is going to die of starvation. He stubbornly trudges onward.

But wait…. what was that smell? Heavenly, impossible, delicious, Wyer followed his nose and finds a miracle, a small camp with a bumbling pot set over a small fire. Without the lack of fear that he should have for a strange camp in a strange land, with his last reserve of energy, he stumbles into the camp and collapses before the fire unconscious.

Barikhol trudged along, just leaving the Anuroch Desert with Armond .  It had been a long hard trek, and Barikhol and Armond had run out of rations and water, with only a small cask of blueberry wine left that he had brought from the temple.  Thankfully, he spied light from a campfire a short distance away.  Hopefully these were travelers, and not orcs or goblins, or kobolds, which were known to inhabit the area. Armond gave Barikhol directions and said he will be there shortly.

As Barikhol moved closer, he smelled a wonderful scent, possibly potato soup!  Knowing that no monster could cook something that smelled so delicious, Barikhol strode into the camp, hoping that he could trade some of his blueberry wine for supper.  Upon stepping into the firelight, the first thing that Barikhol saw was a large man in chain mail armed with a spoon standing over a bloody and beaten body!  Barikhol had seen the masters of his order use unusual weapons, but to do this to someone with a spoon was frightening!  The poor man on the ground had no chance!

Barikhol quickly stepped in front of the prone man, ready to defend him from the spoon wielding brute.  The brute backed away with a laugh, and quickly explained the situation.

Josephus , having explained the situation invited Barikhol to stay to eat.  During this time, Josephus and Barikhol eased Wyer into a sitting position and spooned stew into his mouth and gave him water.  Armond returned to see this situation and asked "what happened?" Eventually, Wyer came around enough to explain what he was doing in the area.

Tyelknowle Collaborative Adventure | Home | Character Collaborative Adventures | Leokas and Rowena

Game 27

Game Day

Game Date: 04/28/2018

TLDR

Red Larch was attacked. Air Cult, used Devastation Orbs. People died. Heroes saved the day.

Barikhol returned.

Detailed Entry

Barikhol has still been missing for a while now. The heroes want to go look for him, but Leokas suggest that they don’t know how to cure him. After some conversations it was decided that Leo, Armond, and Rowena would go to the library and start researching.

Grimble decided to hit the streets to see if he could find any leads as to where Barikhol may be. Grimble ran into Grund pushing his pickle cart sporting a shiny badge that read deputy. The streets are crowded the market is full. Grimble says hello to Grund and learns why there are so many people.

Red Larch has gotten some notoriety due to the Heroes of Red Larch living there. Grimble has noticed that the town has had more visitors, but didn’t really put it together that the visitors may be there for them.

Grund also mentions his sister is coming to visit. Grunds family never visits, they also don’t live too far from Red Larch. It is kind of clear Grunds family doesn’t want to make the effort. Grund also tells Grimble a story about the rumors he has heard about Barikhol and how he is a cursed beast now.

After the conversation had ended, Grimble starts to walk away when he hears Grund say “Hey! What is that? What do you have?” Grimble, being a little curious starts to make his way back to where Grund is. It is hard to see through the crowded streets. Grimble pushes through a group of people when a loud burst of energy explodes out of an orb and Grimble gets knocked to the ground.

It hurt, like an uppercut from a god hurt. Grimbles ears were ringing, He was a little daized from the blow, but he quickly snapped out of it. This Orb killed many. If there wasn’t so many people in the way, Grimble may have even been dead as well. Grimble got up to check on the crowd, but most of them were gone. Grund, was wounded badly, but alive.

All around them was an intense hurricane. It was very dangerous to stay outside. Grimble got Grund and anyone else alive inside 9 Hammers and a Keg Brewery. Grinarv saw them coming up the way and ran out to help.

Leokus, Armond, and Rowena take cover, and communicate with each other. They decided this wasn’t a natural storm and they should go out to help the town’s people. Once outside they heard cries and screams all over town so they decided it was best to split up.

Leokus found Marielye (the waitress from the bar that commonly serves the heroes) outside. She was having a tough time getting to shelter. On his way to assist his shield got ripped out of his arm and went flying towards her.

It missed, but imbedded itself in an open door down the street. Leokus got Marielye into the Helm at Highsun where he saw many other people escaping the storm.

Grimble saw Rowena and her fox darting across the way heading towards Endrith’s shop, Vallivoe’s Sundries. Looking over at the shop he could see there was a massive tornado full of junk picked up from Endrith’s shop. He had to make a decision to help and Grimble muttered to himself and finally ran out the door.

He got over to the shop as part of the building was coming apart. He saw Rowena grab Endrith and she pointed at 4 children in the corner. These were the Tarnlar children. Maegla and Halvur Tarnlar are clothiers right next to the Helm at Highsun.

Grimble scooped up the little one and the next oldest jumped on his back and they went running out of the shop as the tornado started swooping it up. He got them up the road to the Butcher’s shop which is a stone building. Dropping them off, he could see Barikhol charging up the street. He screamed his name, but Barikhol couldn’t hear him over the wind.

Barikhol came journeying back to Red Larch. When he got close he saw a storm appear over the city. It was a magical storm and it was very destructive. Barikhol thought about all the people in that city and went running. In the city Barikhol ran into Stannor who was having trouble with his horse. Barikhol grabbed two and helped get them into shelter. While trying Barikhol was hit with a flying wagon. Barikhol’s had to cool his rage, and once he did he was able to get the horses into safety.

He went running out into the streets looking for more people he could help, and that is when he saw the air cultist. Barikhol didn’t think about it. He charged them started fighting.

Leokus ran back out for his Sheild and he saw a man pinned having a beam from a building going threw him. Leo got in there and realized it was Brother Eardon. He told Eardon, this was going to hurt, but to hang on. He braced the beam so when it would lift it would fling Eardon off. This was extremely painful, and if it wasn’t for magic (some questionable), Eardon would most certainly be dead.

Once Leokus got Brother Eardon healed using the blessing from his god, they went outside to seek better shelter. This is when Leokus saw Barikhol go run past two buildings in front of him.

They were heading that way anyway, but once they got out there they saw Barikhol was engaging into a fight with the Cult of the Howling Hatred.

Barikhol, Grimble, and Leokus came together to start fighting them. They started dropping a few of them when they were attacked with a second wave. Brother Eardon started to help.

Brother Eardon reached his magic which was a black icky goo down into the ground and the fallen cult members stood up and started aiding the Heroes of Red Larch. Once more would drop, Eardon would raise more.

After the fight they all sought shelter.

After the storm ended, Endrith raised the dead and took them off for burial. The heroes collected pieces of the orb and started researching it. They also assisted in cleanup and helping gathering people in the town that was not so lucky.

Back at the tavern they were discussing the orb and found a book that explained what it is. While looking at the book, Endrith walks by and points out that he has seen one of those (pointing to the picture in the book). It was red in Yartar.

The heroes discuss that they need to get up there. They also need someone to help navigate the black-market. They send word to Waterdeep for Teria and Sesa. Hopefully they will be able to help.

They also got into an uncomfortable conversation with Barikhol about what he has become and talk to him about curing him.  Leokus went to go get another beer, Rowena whispered to her fox and ran and jumped through a wall, and Armond read something in a book and went running out of the tavern.

Game 12&13 | Home | Game Notes | Game 23 - 26

Game 28.0 (Last Two Years)

Game Day

Game Date: 06/16/18

Detailed Entry

The curse overwhelms Barikhol. He has haunting memories of days he couldn’t control it. Leokas and Barikhol travel far and wide looking for a cure. They tried many things, and had many failures.

Barikhol and Leokas learned about the battle against Bastain while they were away. When they came across a town they followed a fire cult group and found a war room. Barikhol and Leokas read over the map and fire battle plans and realized their side doesn’t stand a chance. That is when Barikhol had the idea, “use me, it’s a full moon”. Leokas was reluctant, but it looked like there wasn’t a better option.

Barikhol went back to the werecreatures camp and asked for them to follow him to the battle field. The weres did at once. On the way they ran and Barikhol could feel his internal instincts take over. Rage, desire, hope, protection, and fear ran through him. Once the moon was in view in the sky he started to change and so did everyone else. All that could be heard was growls and where there was running there is now galloping. Off in the distance the battle could be heard.

In the non-full moon cycles Barikhol somehow found time for his Brewery. With the help of Teria (Barikhol and Teria have spent a lot time together during these last two years), the 9 Hammers and a Keg Brewery has expanded. Grinarv has been a big help “Barikhol you can trust ol’ Grinarv. Grinarv knows how these businesses go and Grinarv will never let you down.”

In the expansion Barikhol along with Father Franz and a few members of the Mud-Bloods started an orphanage. The brewery generated revenue to help get these kids off the street, take care of them, and eventually get them rehoused, trained, and educated.

Leokas spent sleepless hours researching how to cure Barikhol. Many times his mind and body tried to tell him to give up, but Leokas prayed to Palor to give him the endurance to save his friend. He found in his travels that he started connecting more with Palor. Some things would just fall into place and it would leave Leokas wondering if it was coincidence. But they became more and more frequent and many times it turned out that if he wasn’t there people would have died or bad things would have happened.

Leokas remembers Wyer’s teaching on the theology. It finally started to make sense. Every now and then Leokas’ scar would bother him. Random things would happen like he would lose little bits of time or hear something off in the distance. Leokas may not have even related this to his scar.

There was a moment where it started making sense. He teamed up with some of the soldiers who rescued him after he was held prisoner. They were fighting against the earth cult. When out came Marlos. Leokas grabbed his friend and tried to pull him back, but he felt a pain in his chess that made him hesitate. If he reacted he may have been able to pull Nir out of the way before Marlos turned him to stone, but that jolt of pain stopped him.

Leokas dealing with the lost of his old friend and watching others dying at the hands of the earth cult had a moment of fear. That is when he heard Marlos. “We see you Leokas, we know who you are, we know what you and the Heroes of Red Larch are up to. We knew were you were going to be and that is why we are here. We control you. The Elder Eye sees all. You have lost.”

Leokas fought through the pain and the panic. After a quick prayer to Paylor he got whoever was left and they got out of there.

Two months later Leokas was woken up with a vision. He was standing in his home town. It was on fire. The Earth cult was marching through pulling people out of their homes and executing them on the streets. Leokas tried to wake up, but he couldn’t. He felt it, the scar, the elementals were showing him this vision.

Marlos dragged his family out onto the streets. “I know you two, and I know your son is watching.” Leokas’ mother and father were scared. “This is the price you have to pay for your son and his troop interfering with the elemental evil.” and he proceeded to turn them into stone. Then raised a Warhammer known as Ironfang and started to smash it down on his mother and father.

“NOOOOOO!!!!!!!!” a high pitched scream came from somewhere and Leokas felt the sting of something in his chest. Leo opens up his eyes and see Leaf punching him and zapping at his chest to snap Leokas out of it. “You have to get that under control! May master needs you to come to breakfast!” which was an odd thing to say, but leaf seemed to have his priorities sometimes askew when it came to food.

“Wait!” Leokas said, and Leaf hovered in front of him waiting. “Don’t tell Armond.”

“Not my secret, I can’t.” Leaf replied. “But your food is getting cold!”

Rowena exhausted the books she had for research and decided to travel to the elemental planes to learn more about these cults. What she learned is that the Elemental Evil lives in a world between the elements and it is a disease to the elemental planes. The more power it gains the more it will be able to take over the elemental planes. She also learned that the Orbs take a sacrifice to create. Life magic is very powerful and when a life is sacrificed it can create all sorts of disastrous things.

Rowena found she missed planes traveling. When she prepares to travel it is more about preparing herself. The heroes of Red Larch on a normal day would see Rowena doing weird things like running down the streets with her arms out feeling the wind, building sand castles, getting in to water bag fights, and playing with the town’s children “the floor is lava”.

While Rowena was on the Elemental Plane of Water Rowena found Elodin her twin brother working at, now that Rowena sees the place it is obvious that he would be here, the liquid library. “Elodin, my bother, it has been so long.”

“Too long, I go by Enna now.”

Rowena looks over… her sister Enna. “Enna, my sister, how have I missed you.” They hug like long lost syblings should and catch up.

Enna went on the final mission with their grandmother. There was an attack and a blast of magic and Enna woke up being rescued by merfolk getting her to a bubble (cities in the Elemental Plane of Water). Enna was never good at planes travel, that was always Ro’s talent, so she found what she was good at and started doing it.

Rowena asked Enna to come home with her, but Enna told Rowena “I want to, and I really hope to visit one day, but I have a family here.” She takes Rowena to her home down in the channels. “I want you to meet your niece, nephew, and brother in law.” Rowena spent a couple weeks with them while using the library to learn more about the orbs. In the end she went home without her sister, but they now know how to get ahold of each other.

Rowena in a fit of wild magic made two shells that have a pattern weaved in them that is similar to the ones she used on her bag of holding. They can contact each other by holding the shell and whispering their name.

Grimble made it his top priority to hunt and destroy orbs. Grimble would rush off to Dwarf villages to hunt down cult members. One day why visiting Mirabar Grimble found a statue, in the middle of town. It was the heroes of Red Larch. On the face his statue Grimble wore a mask. It was the mask of Gorm. The description on the statue had an inscription “In remembrance of the heroes that saved Mirabar in 1491”

Grimble had a memory of playing on these streets as a child. Grimble and his friend Amnom was playing a game Mosters and Heroes. Grimble was playing the hero dwarf hunting down Amnom the evil elf. They played with sticks and cookware for their swords and shields. Amnom had this move where he would slide past Grimble and catch him in a random leg and flip him over, spinning up to have his wooden spoon right in front of Grimble. “Got you now!” They had a lot of fun playing together.

Grimble was in Waterdeep waiting on a messenger from the Feathergale Knights when a Water Cult Raid happened. The city was hit with a devastation orb. Rain, floods, whirl pools, and more attacked the streets. The cultist ran through the streets attacking civilians and government buildings. Grimble started fighting back. Grimble watched one of the cultist surf up to the top of a shop. They sold the best whiskey in Waterdeep. Grimble grabbed onto his shield and let the current grab hold of him and push his shield up towards the top of the building, pulling Grimble behind.

The fight was down to who was more skilled Grimble with his axe VS the watercult fighter with his hammer. The water cultist was a dwarf. Grimble yelled “Why did you forsake the Dwarf gods? Your kind is killing so many innocents.”

“HA!” the cultist mocked “The dwarf gods are small, weak, they couldn’t save Raven Rock, they couldn’t save Katwaen.”

Grimble thought to himself “where have I heard that name?” he realized he took his eyes off the cultist for a split second, and before he knew it the watercult dwarf slid by him flipping Grimble onto his back. Grimble saw the hammer just above his face.

On instinct Grimble said “Amnom?” We see Grimble swing his foot and then Grimble as a child doing the same thing. One foot goes over the elbow and the other kicks the hammer swinging it back up to the attackers face and pulling Grimble up from the ground.

The watercult attacker said outloud “Grimble?” as Grimble took the cult member down and kicked off his helmet. Grimble had his axe raised high and Amnom looked into his face and saw the face of Gorm. Amnom begun to cry and beg. Grimble brought his axe down and crushed the helmet.

“Go.” Grimble said “Go home. Just… go home.” Amnom got up and ran.

Game 27.1 | Home | Game Notes | Game 28.1

Game 30 (with a note about 29)

Game Day

Game Date: 08/25/2018

Down into the Howling Caves

Detailed Entry

In our last story the heroes explored the Fane of the Eye. This is on a plane that is in-between the 4 elemental planes. The heroes learned the Elemental Evil is destroying the elemental planes. The stronger he becomes the more his magic will over power the elemental’s magic. The heroes met some lizard folk, fought some rust monsters, got lured by harpies, and almost got into it with a grell (a floating brain with a beak). They came across a deep pit and remembering the riddle, they traveled into here first.

There are four brothers in this world that were all born together:

The first sings a song that is never good,

The second runs and never wearies,

The third drinks and is ever thirsty,

And the fourth eats and is never full.

They repelled down for what felt like an eternity. When they finally hit the bottom, it was pitch black. Everyone but Leokas could see. Leo prayed for light on his weapon to help him navigate the caves.

The first room they came to they noticed a lot of dead bodies on the ground. The only sound in the room was wind coming form 3 fissures in the wall. Once Grimble stepped in he feel to his knees. The air was sucked out of his lungs. He crawled back and finally caught his breath. Rowena summoned her earth hand to go into the room and grab the only thing of value which appeared to be a dead drow and bring her out.

She had some neat things on her. She had a scroll, two ruby daggers, and armor. After looting her the heroes traveled further into the cave. They pasted a chasm that stormed. In it, about 10 feet down, they could see storm clouds and lightning that traveled through it. The next room they came to was cold.

It was about 30 degrees below zero cold. It is really hard to walk through this room. In the middle there was a pond that is completely iced over. In the pond is a medium creature floating around 10+ feet below the surface. Once everyone got in there Leokas took the hardest hit from the cold. He also noticed the creature, and looking closer he could see it was a human body that looks boiled.

At this time they could feel the room getting warmer. The ice started melting at a rapid rate. By the time they just leaped out of the room the pond started boiling. Sitting in the next room the heroes Barikhol and Grimble put together this cave belongs to the elemental evil god Yan-C-Bin.

{Flashback}

The heroes of Red Larch are sitting in the Helm at Highsun. This was in the time after Barikhol had a vision and saw the four leaders of the cults. They listened to Armond read from the book he received from the Bard Bellamir.

“The 4 cults of Earth, Fire, Wind, and Water worship the Evil Eye known as the Elemental Evil, but the god of the cursed elements has bestowed his will onto four others.

Ogremoch , The Prince of Evil Earth: A creature from the Plane of Earth became a lesser god to lead the Earth Cults into a path to serve the Elemental Evil. Ogremoch was the first to come to Faerun. Stories cannot pinpoint when, but it has been for more years than some elves remember.  As all creatures of the rock do, he laid in wait for the world to come to him.

A very powerful and rich man by the name of Marlos Urnrayle built a castle on the land Ogremoch watched over. Marlos began life as a human aristocrat, born into a wealthy Cormyrean family. He squandered his family’s wealth on endless self-indulgence, seeking more questionable forms of entertainment through the years. The Urnrayle estate became known as a place of outrageous masquerades, bizarre banquets, and grotesque orgies. Marlos required his guests to don ugly or monstrous masks, thus ensuring that no one’s beauty would outshine his own.

As he began to age Marlos’ beauty began to fade. Marlos saw movement out his castle’s window and when he looked he saw nothing but a very large hill. ‘I could have sworn that hill was only visible out the other window over there…’ He took his horse and road up to the hill ‘Did my eyes deceive me or does my beauty move mountains?’ he jokingly asked to the hill.

As he was about to leave he heard a deep rumble ‘your beauty fades with time. Your people grow fewer. Soon you will be more attached to the earth than I.’ Marlos fell off his horse and his horse took off running back to the castle.

‘who?... who said that?’ Marlos asked looking around for someone.

The hill stood up and rose to great hights, ‘I have a gift for you.’ A ring came rolling off of the side of Ogremoch body and landed at Marlos’ feet. ‘Wear this and your followers will stay with you forever.’

Marlos put on the ring and walked up to the nearby lake. His reflection was young again. His beauty fully returned. Along with it his followers came back and Marlos’ life went back to the way he loved it. Marlos is vain and cruel, an extreme narcissist who delights in surrounding himself with objects of beauty and luxurious comforts. He had many wives and husbands for he loved beauty.

Over the years he became quick to anger and jealousy. When he caught one of his wives sleeping with one of his husbands he lashed out, grabbed the bed by the post, and snapped it in half. The lovers froze and slammed to the floor and made a thump much louder than expected. When Marlos looked at them they were solid stone that is when he heard the hissing in his hair. He knew what he finally become.

Olhydra , the princess of Evil Water: When she was blessed with the power of the Elemental Evil she came to Faerun to see for herself what followers she would prefer. The first people she saw was a fishermen’s boat.

On board there was a boy. He was the son of an abusive father. His father would cut him, punch him, and he would instruct his crew to help ‘make a man’ out of his son and they would do the same. He would throw his son overboard during storms to make him strong and learn to swim the sea. He would lock his son in a box when he would find him playing. He took his child’s shoes on hot days and the boy would have to burn his feet trying to make his way across the boat. The boy hated life and hated everyone in the world, for life on the boat was all he knew.

One day the boat was attacked by pirates. Olhydra looked down and saw the boy holding a knife pointedly at one of the pirates. The pirate threw him overboard and Olhydra caught him. ‘You will be my prince.’ She said to him. ‘I shall name you Gar.’ When she splashed Gar back onto the fisherman’s boat his father and the crew had been killed.

The pirates turned to this boy and the one that threw him over came walking up to him laughing ‘Boy! You are a stubborn fellow. You would do fine on my crew.’ The child shook his head and attacked. With the full power of Olhydra behind him the captain never stood a chance and dropped quicker than anyone would believe. He turned to the rest of the men and said in a wavy voice ‘You follow us now!’

Over the years Gar devoted himself to the ocean, learning its secrets and powerful water magic. He loved his crew and taught many of them water tricks. He despised any that were not his crew, remembering only his harsh treatment by the merchant crew. But in time he became aware of a call to a higher purpose, impelling him to find other examples of human flotsam and teach them about the power of the sea.

Gar’s visions led him to the secret waters beneath the Sumber Hills. He found a hidden cavern temple, on whose altar lay a powerful magical trident. Sensing its power, Gar took up the weapon and began to call his cult to join him in the Temple of the Crushing Wave.

Imix , the Prince of Evil Flame: On the Plain of Burnt Dreams, an island in the Blazing Sea of the Elemental Plane of Fire, rose a volcano. Inside was the Temple of Ultimate Consumption, a pyramid surrounded by volcanic rock in the middle of a lake of fire. Imix was approached by the Evil Eye and he fought to cast it out of his temple.

The Eye defeated him with one blow and Imix bowed his head for the first time to a higher power.

Vanifer was born and raised in the crushing poverty of Calimport’s poorest quarters, armed with only her cunning intelligence. In her youth, she learned to dance for coin and slowly worked her way up from the wine sinks of the laborers’ districts to the elegant chambers of the city’s nobles. She mastered minor fire magic to distinguish herself from other dancers and incorporated flame into her routine. Her talents grew, and soon she caught the eye of a pasha and became his concubine. But even as she enjoyed the gifts he lavished on her, Vanifer hated the pasha for seeing her as a mere trophy. She left before long, robbing the pasha of a small fortune in jewelry and setting fire to his palace.

Imix first saw Vanifer when she was practicing her fire dancing. She was the first mortal to truly understand the way of the flame. He wanted her. He whispered in her ear and taught her things. She fell in love with the power that he gave and she gave herself to him. Imix took her and changed her that very night. Upon taking her their embrace started a flame of legion. Not only did Vanifer lose all her worldly possessions, the whole city block went up in flames that night. Vanifer became one with the flame. She and her husband Imix traveled to Baldur’s Gate in the poor neighborhood known as Little Calimshan.

There she opened a school of dance. Her gift for fire attracted other sorts of students. She became the leader of a cult of fire worshipers. There she remained for many years, until dreams and visions impelled her to seek out a lost dungeon in the North. On the altar of a forgotten temple she found the dagger Tinderstrike. Armed with this powerful weapon, Vanifer resolved to establish a new chapter of her cult beneath the Sumber Hills.

Yan-C-Bin , the Prince of Evil Air: Yan-C-Bin commonly appeared to his followers as a tall, thin, elderly humanoid with long hair flowing in the wind. His true form was akin to a tornado.

Yan-C-Bin was a being of great wisdom and pure malice. His plans began at the forging of the world. The most subtle of the Princes, he operated unseen and studied his foes from afar, attacking swiftly and vanishing before they could strike back. He cared nothing for those that worshiped him as a god or offered him prayer and sacrifice. All he cared about was seeing realm after realm torn apart by winds.

The Elemental Evil took notice of Yan-C-Bin and offered him power. Yan-C-Bin wanted nothing to do with it as he was fine on his own. But then the Evil Eye saw into his soul and offered him other beings of power couldn’t, the power to destroy Ogremoch. ‘As the wind you will finally be able to move the mountain.’

Over the years Yan-C-Bin looked to The Evil Eye as a father.

Aerisi grew up in an enchanted castle in a remote part of Faerie, surrounded by tales, histories, and tomes of magic. She passed her early years playing games, practicing enchantments, and imagining herself as one of the avariel (winged elves) from her storybooks. Her parents sheltered her from the conflicts of Faerun, and she came of age with a tender and fragile disposition.

Eventually her parents decided it was time for their daughter to engage in elven society, and they brought her to the hidden city of Evereska. Her parents then realized their grave mistake. In pampering and sheltering their daughter, they had raised not a young lady but a spoiled child. Accustomed to having all she desired, the princess erupted into tantrums whenever she was denied her slightest whim, and the moon elves of Evereska could hardly endure her. This is when Yan-C-Bin took notice on the child.

Aerisi felt powerless among the moon elves. Although she had become a skilled enchanter in Faerie, her people were resistant to such charms. In her dreams she began to envision herself as one of the winged elves from her storybooks. She wished to control the wind and go wherever she liked, and to punish those who offended her. The childlike fantasies of her youth became dark visions where she ruled the storms and the air itself. She dreamed of an old mystic with brown skin and white hair, who promised to teach her all she desired to know—a vision of Yan-C-Bin, the Prince of Evil Air. Aerisi turned her study to elemental air, learning the secret of flight and escaping Evereska to follow the deluded visions of her dreams.

Aerisi’s visions led her to a strange altar in a cavern beneath the Sumber Hills, where she acquired the spear Windvane. Driven by Yan-C-Bin, she dubbed herself a queen and set out to find followers to rule. Her enchantments helped fill the ranks of the Cult of the Howling Hatred with initiates hopelessly devoted to her.

Armond places the book down and looks to his friends. This is what we’re up against. I thought these were just stories, but now that Barikhol describes the people he saw in his visions, I don’t that anymore.

{End Flashback}

Barikhol scouted ahead and came into a room where he heard a “whoosh, splat, whoosh, splat”. Looking into the room he could see an air elemental with body parts floating inside him and splatters of gore all around the room. In the middle of the room there is a large hole that extends further up than any he could see.

The next room Barikhol walked into and he could hear a familiar voice that he had not heard for a long time. “Son? Is that you? I waited for you. Where did you go?”

When other entered the room:

Rowena: “Granddaughter? Oh I have missed you. Come home. Give up this task."

Grimble: “You will never be a mantel of Grom. You will never hold the axe or the hammer. You will never be good enough.”

Leokas: “Why did you tell them where we were? Why did you leave us to die? You could have helped. With you there we could have lived.”

Odert: He responds in Rowena’s head “Princess? Princess? Is that you?”

Looking around the room, the heroes couldn’t figure out where the sounds were coming from. Traveling on to the next room. They saw someone. The wind would collide and an image of someone was standing there.

Barikhol: Tyria

Grimble: A training buddy from his past.

Rowena: Armond

Leokas: The woman who branded him.

The next room they came to they were attacked by Svirfneblin Spirits. The room looks like where they tested the first model of the Devastation Orb. The angry specters were what was left in the room. After putting them to rest they moved on to the next room.

In here there was a nycaloth. This ugly creature was torturing others hanging from the ceiling by their feet. In that group there is a Dark Elf, an aarakocra, and two humans. After Barikhol updated the group what was in there, they ran in for the attack. This creature was tricky. He threw darkness over the group and started attacking Leokas. Leo, pulled out an item he had been hanging on to for quite some time, the (blah). After releasing it and saying a little prayer the room lit up.

Leo could tell that the creature was surprised. He swung and hit Leo and teleported. Barikhol ran up and started attacking the creature as soon as he reappeared. The creatures trying to get away and get a couple good swings in teleports again. He was blasted with magic missiles from Rowena’s wand, struck hard by Gimbles axe, bashed with Leokas mace, and brought down by Barikhol’s fist.

After the fight they untied the aarakocra and let him go, but the drow Grimble put down. “They are evil, their kind hunt and kill dwarfs, he has killed many, and if we let him go… he will kill many more. It is a mercy really.”

The heroes needed a rest. Leo did a powerful group heal before they began their long rest.

Game 28.1 | Home | Game Notes | Game 19

Game 19

Game Day

Game Date: 08/02/17

Date in Play: 11/7/1491

Detailed Entry

The group catches Leokus up with what has been going on in the Hills.
The heroes went shopping around town

Armond bought a riding horse
Barikhol and Grimble bought a horse and wagon
Barikhol bought silver gloves (Not really this is just story)
Erin wants to invest into a Library business "Information collection and disbursement"
Barikhol, winked at his one eye friend, He gain inspiration (note this for later actions)

They get meeting from Otho

Otho tells them Ty capture was planned. He was needed to get a Lord of waterdeep out of prison.
He mentions that Cult activities are happening in other places throughout the sword coast.
He also mentions that the monastery is missing monks and they filled the place up with creatures

The monks were heading north
There may be clues in the monastery as to where.

Justran comes by the table to take everyone's orders
Barikhol orders a Rare stake

Grimble orders one with him, with a side of potatoes.
Barikhol tears into it. This is the first time he is feeling like he is really eating.
Grimble realizes he would like his steak done a little more.

Armond waits on the long road for Imusek along with the rest of the party.

Rowena (on seeing him) cast mage armor
Imusek has cloaked his creatures.

One of the creatures "the Lord of Lance Rock" his son. Orioth

Armond lets Leo know that it is ok to be wary.
I want to talk about a magic charge 100gp (Armond pays it)
Rowena talked about being stabbed by the knife (1:37:00) Imusek "yes, my son is really sorry about that, aren’t you son?" The zombie Lord of Lance Rock starts nodding.
I am worried about my safety. "you have nothing to fear from the cleric" after agreeing with his son "well that makes us feel 50% better."
Imuske walks around the town.
Harburk stops Armond in town "I see the Necro is back." "I don't like him."
"Has he actually harmed anyone?" Row: "Me. Well if he never had his son I wouldn't have been captured."

Imusk talks about:

Small talk with Barikhol and Leokus
What brought your interest into the earth cult?

Armond talks about their history of running into them.
What is their goal?

Short sighted to wreak havoc
They are taking an ancient deity or power source they are trying to appease.  "gods like that are not worth following."

Do you follow a god?

Oh, yes. I follow the teaching of Vashroon.
Armond explains: Vashroon was a human that through necromancy ascended to godhood.
Barkhol: Do you wish to become that?
"A god? No… that is way too much responsibility"
Row: "Well you can't take responsibility for your offspring."

Armond shows Vashroon a picture of the Evil eye

Imusk explains that is what drove his son away from the family.
Armond: that is a symbol that is linked to the earth cult.

What a small world we live in. It dove him into madness

B: You raise dead people

My son was alive when I raised him.

Barikhol points out they were talking about his servants.

Ahhh, can't a man just raise his family in piece?
They are your family?
They are a part of me, yes.
They sign up for this.
Like a permission slip?
In our tribe you sign over your death to serve and protect the head of houses.
You agree to give someone full control of your body once you die?
They're meat.

Armond: asks about the knife

The knife can trap a soul or it could release a soul.
Armond asks about removing Odert
Imusek apologizes that his son used the knife in a way of a sin. Oderts soul binding is permanent. Once she dies her soul may pass on, but I am not sure what will happen to the other one inside of you.
The knife may not help you, but there may be something one can do.

Rowena ask about his magic

The magic I have been using for years have been fine, but the newer studies I have notices fluctuations in their castings. The magic sometimes will just fizzle out without warning.

Rowena had a dream:

The fox was there wobbling and snuggles with Ro, when she holds it she feels cold.

The go in to the Monastery through the back.

Once inside they run into a pair of Gricks

After the fights one of Imusks skeletons got injured. Imuske started patching him up.

They continue to the left and go in the great hall where they ran into 3 interesting baboon like creatures. They are capable of spiting fire.

They charge the door start slashing and lighting up the characters.
The heroes bust in and start taking them out. During the fight they took a lot of damage, but luckily they have a cleric now that they don't send out to check for traps.

They take a beat to heal up, Rowena goes to check out the stairs. There was a large growl that came from down there and the stairs snapped. Rowena dived back to not fall down the trap.

They search the room and find a lever. Barikhol finally figures out how to work the puzzle to lock the lever in place, which should reset the stairs.

They decide to explore more of the monastery. They travel to the west. In the room they find a Drakon. It is a large winged creature.

Armond cast this spell that makes an inky black darkness. The darkness reached out an lashed at the creature. The creature few around to room trying to find an out, but could not. After a few moments it finally finds the door and starts to try and get out. The "heroes?" hold it back where it eventually dies.
The moment it dropped everyone looked, scared at Armond, "What?"

The heroes continue through the monastery. Most of the rooms are empty.

In the entrance there are two earth guards. The "heroes?" convenes them to lay down their arms. They questioned them:

Where is the rest of the earth cult? We don't know, we have been gone for 2 tenday.
Where would they have headed? We still don't know
They tried to roam the monastery, but the place is filled up with monsters.

Game 30 (with a note about 29) | Home | Game Notes | Game 20

Leokas and Rowena

Stories

Leokas and Rowena

“I show up here thinking I've found another opportunity to do some good and spread the word of Pelor, and yet I've been here 3 days and nothing. Everything seems to be fine, nobody needs my help... so much for being a beacon of hope and champion for Pelor; at this rate I'll not have a single good deed to report back to Wyer when I see him next; whenever that might be. Guess  I'll continue on, maybe by the time I've reached home I'll have some good stories worth telling.”

Leokas packs his things, pays the innkeep for his lodging, and sets off out of town. Shortly after leaving the town “gates” (if they had them) he is passed by a young man sprinting quickly by.

“Geez kid, slow it down, you're young, no need to work so hard to stay in shape”

 “Help! Somebody, please help!”  Leokas turns around to see what's going on and sees the same kid that just blew past him moments ago, yelling in between gasped breaths, seeking help. By the time Leokas walks back to the kid a few of the townspeople have already gathered around concerned.

“...she's dying, nothing we've tried is helping, please can't anybody help us?”

Leokas: “whoa, whoa kid, catch your breath, and then start from the beginning”

After hearing the kid out Leokas treks out to the small homestead where the kids grandmother lives by herself with her few livestock, and not much else. He examined the woman and healed her as much as he could, but even his new found skills and magic wouldn't stop her from dying; he stabilized her and eased some of the pain, but he maybe bought her another month.

Leokas: “I'm sorry kid, this is the best I can do for now, I'm currently at my limit with this, but I think I might be able to help further. I just need to get some help first in order to do so; I promise I'll try my best to hurry back here”

Leokas sets out in search of further knowledge and understanding of this disease or curse.

 “I know I've heard mention of this somewhere, maybe if I can find a temple or library nearby I can figure out what this is, and how to fix it.”

After to speaking to some of the locals, Leokas discovers that the Library of Loudwater is nearby. A half day of walking leads him to worn but solid doors. There is a surprising amount of activity; staffers bustle about reshelving books, lead patrons to various areas of the library, and one of them appears to be cleaning a strange smelling substance off of the floor…

Tentatively, Leokas approaches the front desk. An ancient looks gnomish woman sits on a high stool, scratching some words into the tome before her.

“Ahem...” Leokas coughs.

The pen stops scratching. The woman glances up, notices Leokas before her, then carefully sets the quill aside before pushing her cracked spectacles up her nose. “Yes?”

“I am a cleric of <deity>. I’ve come looking for information about an illness. I was hoping I could discuss it with someone that may be able to further direct my research.”

“Hmmm,” the old woman croaks. “What information do you have about it?”

“Well, it’s affecting an elderly human just outside of Loudwater . Her grandson said she started feeling dizzy and seeing inexplicable visions. I’ve done what I could to stabilize her vitals, but I’m afraid I’ve never come across anything like this before.”

“That’s not much to go on, sonny.”

Leokas ’ face falls.

“But, I’d recommend talking to Rowena . She may be able to help.” The librarian directs him to an upstairs workshop where he is likely to find her. The climb up the winding staircase is surprisingly taxing. As Leokas catches his breath, he notices the bookcases contain tomes with strange symbols etched into their spines. Not to be distracted from his mission, he finds the dark hallway hidden behind the mysterious tomes. Dancing light flickers beneath the door at the end. As he raises his hand to knock, the door silently swings open, and Leokas hesitantly looks inside.

“Oh hello,” a chipper voice says. A unicorn stands in the corner of the room.

“Uhmm…” he begins, staring at the beast. Suddenly, the unicorn disappears. A smiling face appears around the door in front of him.

“Oh, you look grim. Why sad? Did you see that unicorn? She was beautiful, wasn’t she?” Leokas ’ eyes are drawn to the strange fox ears pointing out of the girl’s auburn hair. Noticing his stare, the girl quirks an eyebrow in the “my eyes are down here” manner. One of her ears twitches.

“The woman downstairs said I should ask you for information about a new illness I’ve seen…” Leokas regains his composure and iterates to her what he knows.

“Hmm,” Rowena muses. “I think I read something similar a book about planar poisoning before. Let’s go see if we can find it.” As Rowena leads him out of the room, he notices a flump waving at them from a jar on her desk. She leads Leokas past the tomes with unintelligible symbols to the opposite side of the staircase, then reaches up and pulls down a book with dark blue binding. Leokas takes the book from her and opens it to begin reading, but the writing inside the book keeps shifting and moving, preventing it from being legible. “Huh,” says Rowena . “That’s new.”

"So, it's not just me then? These books aren't normally like this?"

"Nope, not when I read it last" said Rowena

"This is bizarre, I know I don't consider myself a learned man really, but I'm not a mindless oaf either; it's almost like when you try to read a book in a dream..."

At that moment Leokas feels a tiny flash of divine light in his subconscious and hears "Wake up!, I don't believe I chose you to triumph my cause, simply to watch you flounder in your sleep!"

I immediately snap awake and find myself in bed, rather sweaty and with a tremendous headache. Realizing that I'm still at my lodgings for the evening, I start to calm down but can't shake the nagging feeling that this wasn't just a random dream, that something wasn't quite right here. I get up, don my armor, and head off towards where the library was in my dream. Soon enough I find it, exactly where it should be, but being the middle of the night it takes a while and many raps of the knocker before someone answers the door.

"Excuse me, but the library is closed for the night, please do come back tomorrow" says the attendant in her night gown, and proceeds to close the door; before she can get the door fully closed I jam my foot in the doorway. As she turns back around with that "what do you think you're doing look" I begin explaining what I just experienced, and asked her if there was someone named Rowena that worked there. She said yes and now seeing on her face that she shared my concern she let me in and led me to the study up those same winding stairs with the same weird books. I let her knock on the door a few times with no answer before I push it open slowly and begin to pull my shield off my back just in case; when we find her face down sound asleep on a desk. The two of us gently walk over to her, while I eye the whole room, packed full of books, and half expecting to see that silly unicorn in the corner. The attendant tries to shake her awake, but nothing happens; I walk over and give it a slightly firmer try, and yet still nothing. I place my hand over the symbol of Pelor and focus for a moment, asking for his help, and then I lay my hands on Rowena in an attempt to restore her back to her normal state.

She slowly lifts her head blinking, and rubbing the sleep out of her eyes, looking a little confused.

*Yawning* "...Huh?... but....why am I here" looking at the desk "...we were.. just over there looking at a book, and it was acting rather bizarre..."

I introduce myself, formally, and explain that we hadn't actually met just yet, not in person at least; "..it seems we were both somehow stuck in the same dream together."

After a few more minutes of conversation and pondering over what just happened to the two of us, she leads me back over to the same book. Apprehensive I open it up, and thankfully this time the words aren't running around all over the place. We figure out what the ailment is, and what's required of me to cure it. I think both Rowena and the attendant for their time, and I set off now that it's early morning, eager to gather the remaining components I need and get back to the old lady to ease her suffering.

Arriving at the cabin just a few days’ shy of the month prognosis I gave, I was happily pleased to find that she was still hanging on, if just barely, with her grandson at her side tending to her aid. Happy to see me back, he gladly helps me prepare the necessary items and luckily enough I was able to cure her of her malady.

Afterwards, I explain to the boy what was going on, and let him know to try and send word to me if anything like this happens again; and to keep an eye on his grandma, to see if she does anything strange, as this isn't a normal illness for someone to come across. We part ways and I settle back into my journey, all the while thinking about the strange girl with the furry ears.

Josephus Collaborative Adventure | Home | Character Collaborative Adventures | Next

Game 22

Game Day

Game Date: 11/18/2017

Date in Play: 11/25/1491

TLDR

They killed Hellenrae, The town was under attack, they split up to stop the Construct Monster and Save the town.

They saved the town, Barikhol road the worm, stopped the creation of an evil temple, and the wild mage went wild everywhere.

Detailed Entry

Flashback to Rowena

She was experiencing Wild Surges while in prison and trying to hold them back
She was looking worse than the rest of the heroes. Her body is obviously taking too much stress from this experience
At one point when her magic started sparking and she looked incredibly weak her fox comes up and lays down by her side. She instantly starts to feel better.
Each time she starts experiencing surges her fox continues to do this and over time the fox starts looking more and more wounded.
This is when We see Rowena 's island of magic and in the middle a black spot forms.

The heroes return back into battle with the Stone Construct.

Leokus doesn't want anybody else, and when he prays to Palor he touches himself.
Rowena was hit by a monk and she could feel her losing grip of haste, but she pulls it back together.
The Construct turns purple and after a couple seconds of flashing it responds "I understand. I will go now master."

Rowena and Barikhol chased after it.

They got up to a chasm and the Construct jumped down.
About 1000 feet across they can make out a cave that is shimmering. They assume the Construct is heading that way.
Barikhol jumps and lands on a Ramerhas. He slips off but grabs one of the tentacles from the face and wraps around to create makeshift rains

Rowena starts running back to the others and sees her fox. She can see the fox running beside her. Her magic sparks and she can see the fox gain energy. Then she has a moment of realization. The fox is powered by her wild magic. Suppressing that magic should be ripping her apart, but instead it is ripping her sprit fox apart. She sparks again and fox jumps and lands in front of her hardening the snow around Rowena 's feet creating a like snowboard. She goes zooming down the hillside towards her friends. By the time they reach the doors she comes sliding up beside them.
They go into the city and hear screams of gore. They approach a section of the city and see one of the monks slitting a dwarfs throat.

The heroes run up and about 20 or more monks jumping out of windows and come flying down city streets.
Grimble wearing the mask of Gorm screams GORM! And smashes his hammer down on that monk and they get surrounded.
Armond goes running up and crouches down and swords burst out from him and start slicing through many of them. It starts ripping the monks apart. Other monks are diving out of the way and some are being more vicious and pushing monks into the way to save their lives.
A monks sucks the bricks out from under Leokus and starts blasting them back at him. Leokus swings his shield up and bricks go flying everywhere.
Rowena grabs one of them and starts shocking them and feels the energy go down her other arm and unleash into another Monk
Gorm brings his hammer to two monks but misses their face and it rips open their necks.
Back at the Cave Barikhol follows too close to the Construct and it smashes him up against the wall. Barikhol uses his centering and follows at a much further distance.
Two monks were lifting rocks the throw at Rowena and Armond swings his glave snicker snack and both monks are still standing there as they watch the bricks fall and the bodies separate.
Rowena blast another monk and then she turns invisible.
A bone collector shows up and starts shooting bone shards at the heroes. Grimble goes running and uses Armond to assist and get him up onto the roof to engage with this creature.
Grimble engages with the Bone Collector while the rest of the heroes keep the Monks off him. Grimble takes a hit, but Leokus is there to keep him alive.
The monks continue to pound on the heroes. Armond and an invisible Rowena are jumping around the battle field slinging Eldritch Blast and Fire Bolts.
The Collector gets a powerful strike on Grimble nearly killing him.
Barikhol follows the Construct to an opening in the cave and in the middle on a pedestal sits a box that is displaying a hologram of the Evil Eye . Grimble knows not to let the construct near the middle of the room. He pounds his fist into him and sweeps him trying to stop him but the construct persist.
Armond finishes off the last of the monks on the ground as Rowena jumps up onto the roof. When she lands a couple of monks see the indentations and starts hurling bricks from the roof towards her, but the bricks go flying off into the sky.
Leokus heals Grimble and the sky open up as XXXX (Leo's god) blesses him. Grimble speaks with the power of the gods "I am Gorm" and smashes his hammer down on the collector.
Barikhol leaps off the Construct and kicks the box further away so the creature cannot get to it. He then turns around and starts punching this monster as sparks come flying off his fist as he is pounding into the creature. He brings up his fist high and snaps down on the creatures head where there is a loud crack
The bone collector rises up and opens up. It smashes down on Grimble everyone hears his armor chink and bones start forming around Grimble . Grimble stands up and turns towards Armond and the bones move Grimbles arm to lift his hammer to strike down on Armond . But at the last moment the mask starts glowing and Grimble stops. The air cracks and speaks "No one controls Gorm!" the bones shatter and burst away as Grimble is standing there, but not looking anything like Grimble , he looks like a god. He turns around and smashes away the bones on the collector as Armond leaps over Grimble with is Glave straight out and slices up into the creatures skull.
They make it back to the cave and Grimble realizes this used to be a temple of Gorm. He takes the mask and places it on the alter which sits on top of a fountain. He feels his hammer being guided towards the fountain and he places it in there. When he pulls it back out he is holding a battle axe. That has symbols of Gorm drawn down the side.

Child Topics

(G 23) Who let the Boar Out
(G 26) it's a bird, it's a plane...
(G19) Return to the Monistary
(G27) Shit is going down

Game 16 | Home | Game Notes | Next